<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Retrospectives on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/category/retrospectives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retrospectives on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 23:26:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://davidcraddock.net:9796/category/retrospectives/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Retrospective on 2022</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/12/23/my-personal-retrospective-on-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 23:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/12/23/my-personal-retrospective-on-2022/</guid>
      <description>Every year (when I remember) I do an end-of-year summary to outline what has been going on in my life. I’ve been doing this for a few years now, and it’s a great way to look back on the year and see has happened.&#xA;The Bad: The main bad news of the year is that, contrary to expectations, my Hodgkins Lymphoma cancer was detected again around April after the initial chemotherapy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Story in Tech</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/02/13/my-story-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/02/13/my-story-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write here a bit about how I got into technology and how my career has progressed for those people wanting to get into technology.&#xA;I was lucky enough to be born in a supportive home to good parents. My father was an early entrant into the world of computing, and my birth certificate records his profession as a &amp;lsquo;Computer Science Lecturer&amp;rsquo;, which was very rare at the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective on 2021</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/01/01/retrospective-on-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/01/01/retrospective-on-2021/</guid>
      <description>Well, 2021 has been a bit of a downer in a number of ways. There has been some upsides though.&#xA;I spent the first part of 2021 burned out, as in - totally burned out - of my career and really needing a break. This affected my work. It turns out that unknown to me at the time, I had cancer, Hodgkins Lymophoma, and a lot of my lack of energy and generally feeling awful was down to a large tumor that had been growing my chest for some time and was pressing down on my heart and lungs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 Retrospective – Wow, what a year!</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2021/03/04/2020-retrospective-wow-what-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 19:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2021/03/04/2020-retrospective-wow-what-a-year/</guid>
      <description>I think, for obvious reasons, 2020 has been a year that no-one could really have expected. With COVID-19 and lockdown, a lot of things have changed, both in my life, in everyone&amp;rsquo;s lives, and in the workplace.&#xA;My online DJing setup&#xA;Things that went well I changed medication around March 2020 which has resulted in significant weight loss, as expected. The previous medication was making me put on and retain weight even when I was eating very very little.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Retrospective for Years 2016-19</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2019/03/30/a-retrospective-for-years-2016-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 23:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2019/03/30/a-retrospective-for-years-2016-19/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d update my blog to reflect recent changes in my life, and review what was good and bad about them, as I was doing before.&#xA;The &amp;ldquo;Not Awesome&amp;rdquo;&#xA;My overall health level has got a bit worse over the years. I have had limited success in losing weight. I was going for regular walks nearly every week with a friend of mine, but that has stopped lately. I find it difficult exercising while living in a city, as my favourite activity for excercising is walking, and there are not a huge amount of pleasent walking oppertunities around my area.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
