<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>http://davidcraddock.net/category/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 02:53:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://davidcraddock.net/category/gaming/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Game Collecting</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net/2022/08/09/digital-game-collecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 02:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net/2022/08/09/digital-game-collecting/</guid>
      <description>I have a relatively obscure hobby - I collect digital video games. Quite a few people collect physical games, but I like the advantages of having a large library of gaming options which are just a download away.
Like a lot of collectors, I have more games than I have actually played, or probably will do in my lifetime. I mostly get them via discounted bundles such as HumbleBundle.com, so I rarely play full price for them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a relatively obscure hobby - I collect digital video games. Quite a few
people collect physical games, but I like the advantages of having a large
library of gaming options which are just a download away.</p>
<p>Like a lot of collectors, I have more games than I have actually played, or
probably will do in my lifetime. I mostly get them via discounted bundles such
as <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com">HumbleBundle.com</a>, so I rarely play full price for them.</p>
<p>I use the excellent games launcher <a href="https://playnite.link">Playnite</a> to organize
and consolidate all my games from the various proprietary launchers, such as
Origin and GOG Galaxy. It also downloads a lot of metadata for each game,
including gameplay video trailers, and provides a customizable interface for
everything.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve dipped into emulation for some games that I used to own. But I try and keep
that minimal because of the legal grey area it is under. I have ripped ISOs of
the console games I used to have, before I gave them away to a charity shop.</p>
<p>Some people worry that with digital collections the proprietary launcher company
will go bust, and you will lose access to all your games. To be honest I&rsquo;m not worried
about this as I&rsquo;m fairly sure under that situation they would provide an option
to transfer to a different launcher, or allow downloads of your entire account.
I also use 2-factor authentication on everything, and keep a close eye on
security alerts.</p>
<p>I have been collecting games on Steam since 2004 or so, so I have a large
collection. It is interesting going through the various games and finding out
more about them. I definitely don&rsquo;t play everything, and most games for not very
long, but it is a good distraction from the worries of life.</p>
<p>Here are my statistics from Playnite:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/stats.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
