<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Introversion on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>https://davidcraddock.net/category/introversion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introversion on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.134.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 16:22:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidcraddock.net/category/introversion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introversion, Extroversion and the BBC Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/28/introversion-extroversion-and-being-a-bbc-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 16:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/28/introversion-extroversion-and-being-a-bbc-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://davidcraddock.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/introvert.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://davidcraddock.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/introvert.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;introvert&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you agree with Myers-Briggs personality profiling or not, like fellow BBC&amp;rsquo;er &lt;a href=&#34;http://cubicgarden.com/2015/07/27/being-entp-dyslexic-and-relationships/&#34;&gt;Ian Forrester&lt;/a&gt; I have found them a useful frame of reference from which to discuss my personality, because I see similarities between my perception of me, and the classification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the Myers-Briggs personality profiling, and it has labelled me on several occasions an INTP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INTPs are marked by a quiet, stoic, modest, and aloof exterior that masks strong creativity and enthusiasm for novel possibilities. Their weaknesses include poor organization, insensitivity to social niceties, and a tendency to get lost in abstractions. Keirsey referred to INTPs as Architects, one of the four types belonging to the temperament he called the Rationals
&amp;hellip;
I – Introversion preferred to extraversion: INTPs tend to be quiet and reserved. They generally prefer interacting with a few close friends rather than a wide circle of acquaintances, and they expend energy in social situations (whereas extraverts gain energy).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
