<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/tag/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://davidcraddock.net:9796/tag/ubuntu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tips for new Ubuntu Users</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/09/29/tips-for-new-ubuntu-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/09/29/tips-for-new-ubuntu-users/</guid>
      <description>Here are some extra tips if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started out on Ubuntu.&#xA;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the UI to shut down or reboot your computer. You can do it from the command line. The commands are:&#xA;sudo reboot # to reboot sudo poweroff # to shut down and power off the computer You can get a lot more information on your computers startup and shutdown sequences by removing the default Ubuntu splash screen that obscures this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Backup using Rclone</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/09/24/google-drive-backup-using-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2022/09/24/google-drive-backup-using-rclone/</guid>
      <description>For 8 TB of data storage on Google Drive, plus my own Google organization, I am paying £30/month, which is a pretty good deal.&#xA;I wanted to use this space for backing up my NAS, but it was proving difficult. The program I was recommended for Linux backup, Duplicati, was not the best for this purpose. My backup runs would not complete, they would be slow, and full of syncing errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Enlightenment window manager on Ubuntu 21.10</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2021/11/18/setting-up-enlightenment-window-manager-on-ubuntu-21-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2021/11/18/setting-up-enlightenment-window-manager-on-ubuntu-21-10/</guid>
      <description>Enlightenment is a very underrated window manager choice, in my opinion. It still looks very pretty and is very configurable. There is a packaging bug with the latest version of Enlightement in the 21.10 repo which means it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly. The fix is to set the suid bit on the &amp;rsquo;enlightenment_system&amp;rsquo; binary. So:&#xA;sudo apt install enlightenment sudo find /usr/lib -type f -name enlightenment_system -exec sudo chmod 4755 {} \; Log out of Ubuntu Click the settings cog in the bottom right to change your Window manager to enlightenment Log on and the settings wizard will help you configure Enlightenment </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Kindlefire HDX for Development under Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2014/02/10/kindlefire-hdx-under-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2014/02/10/kindlefire-hdx-under-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to get a Kindlefire HDX running under Ubuntu 12.04 with adb.&#xA;First I needed to setup the udev rules:&#xA;1. Edit /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules as root, and add the following line (create this file if it does not exist):&#xA;SUBSYSTEM==&amp;#34;usb&amp;#34;, ATTRS{idVendor}==&amp;#34;1949&amp;#34;, MODE=&amp;#34;0666&amp;#34; 2. Change the permission of this file by executing the following command as root:&#xA;chmod a+r /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules 3. Reload the rules by executing the following command as root:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android Debug Bridge failing to detect emulators under OSX</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2013/11/17/android-debug-bridge-failing-to-detect-emulators-under-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 02:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2013/11/17/android-debug-bridge-failing-to-detect-emulators-under-osx/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project at the BBC where we are using the Android command-line tools from the Android Developer Tools, to spin up and terminate series of emulators. I noticed a big problem under OSX where &amp;lsquo;adb devices&amp;rsquo; was failing to register emulators occasionally when we started them up, without any error message, even though they were loaded and quite clearly running in a window on OSX. This was a real problem for our project because we needed absolute parity between emulator process being launched and subsequently being detected by adb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirutalHosts on CentOS</title>
      <link>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2009/03/30/virutalhosts-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://davidcraddock.net:9796/2009/03/30/virutalhosts-on-centos/</guid>
      <description>A common task when setting up an Apache webserver under Linux, is writing a httpd.conf file. The httpd.conf file is the main configuration file for Apache. One of the main reasons to edit the httpd.conf file is to setup virtual hosts In Apache. A Virtual host configuration allows several different domains to be run off a single instance of Apache, on a single IP. Each host is a &amp;lsquo;Virtual host&amp;rsquo;, and typically has a different web root, log file, and any number of subdomains aliased to it.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
