<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Serato on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>https://davidcraddock.net/tag/serato/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serato on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 02:56:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidcraddock.net/tag/serato/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Current Twitch DJ Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/27/current-dj-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 02:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/27/current-dj-setup/</guid>
      <description> Click to view full diagram
Hardware 2 x Reloop 8000mk2 turntables Roland 707m Mixer and DJ Controller 2015 Macbook Pro (DJ Laptop) SoundSwitch USB -&amp;gt; DMX interface, attached to broadcast PC Beatstep MIDI Controller mapped for controlling SoundSwitch, attached to broadcast PC Vestax VCM-600 MIDI Controller used for controlling Resolume, attached to broadcast PC AKAI LPD8 MIDI Controller used for controlling Serato&amp;rsquo;s FX, attached to DJ laptop Rode Soundcaster Pro microphone used as a DJ mic 4 x Phillips Hue Colour Bulbs in lamps Phillips Hue Lightstrip Behringer UMC1820 Sound Interface connected to broadcast PC, attached to broadcast PC 2 x Logitech C920 Cameras used for capturing video for streaming, attached to broadcast PC Software SoundSwitch lighting software running on broadcast PC Resolume Avenue running on broadcast PC Streamlabs OBS running on broadcast PC Serato DJ Pro software running on DJ laptop </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pioneer DDJ-SR Serato Controller Review</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/09/03/pioneer-ddj-sr-serato-controller-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/09/03/pioneer-ddj-sr-serato-controller-review/</guid>
      <description>I decided to buy the DDJ-SR controller because it was cheaper than even the cheapest pair of Pioneer CDJs. I’m no stranger to using a laptop and controller, before the DDJ-SR I used my trusty Faderfox DJ2 controller, which is a basic no-frills ‘play buttons, 3 EQs, crossfader and volume faders’ unit.
I was considering getting the Native Instruments Traktor S4 DJ controller, which is one of the most popular full-size controllers for Traktor.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
