<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>https://davidcraddock.net/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <image>
      <title>DavidCraddock.net</title>
      <url>https://davidcraddock.net/mugshot.png</url>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/mugshot.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>David Paul Craddock</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:08:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidcraddock.net/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>vWorkbench</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/vworkbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 17:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/vworkbench/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;vWorkbench&amp;rdquo; is my own personal Vim9-based development environment and writing environment that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to &amp;lsquo;spin out&amp;rsquo; into an open source project that is stable enough, reusable enough and well-documented enough to be used by others.
https://github.com/wordswords/dotfiles.git - this is the current version of my development environment that I use as much as possible, both in personal and work situations.
https://github.com/wordswords/dotfiles/blob/master/README.md - this is the documentation on my development environment, which I absolutely try and keep up to date.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Research</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/security-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 03:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/security-research/</guid>
      <description>I am currently familiarising myself with tools to implement cyber security solutions.
This is in preparation for my research project as part of the MSc Cyber Security masters I&amp;rsquo;m taking from the University of London via distance learning.
This research is strictly for informational purposes and I don&amp;rsquo;t do anything criminal with it.
Red Team Wardriving and Wifi cracking I have two Raspberry Pi Zeros configured headless with pwnagotchi to automatically capture wifi handshakes hashes to crack later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Bike</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 22:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/my-bike/</guid>
      <description>Bike 1 - Electric Mountain Bike I use this for mostly getting out of the city and into some nature. It is a long-range bike.
Himiway Zebra Electric Mountain Bike 2023 Version (road legal, top electric-assisted speed 15mph, max. pull 400lbs) 2x official batteries (40-80 miles on a single charge each) 2x battery chargers Two spare tires Spare inner tube Electric fat tire pump Metal tire levers Adjustable wrench Chain tool for removing chain links Chain cleaner tool &amp;ldquo;MuckOff&amp;rdquo; bike cleaning kit Small first aid kit Compass Himiway fold-out cycle toolkit Energy bars + nuts 2x cycle frame bags 2x Rockbros waterproof pannier bags Rockbros Handlebar bag Rockbros Mobile phone holder bag Electric bike horn Bike bell Himiway cycle helmet with front light 4x vaccum thermos 750ml flasks for water All-weather MTB grips for handlebar Fingerless MTB gloves for warmer weather Wraparound anti-glare sun glasses for protection against surface dirt etc Wraparound cycle goggles with different visors Light backpack suitable for cycling Goretex water-resistant high-vis cycle jacket VEVOR Cycle Bike Cargo Trailer Bike 2 - City Electric Cargo Bike My wife and I use this as a bike for getting shopping and a general-purpose car replacement, as well as volunteering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Mobile Laptop Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-mobile-laptop-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/my-mobile-laptop-setup/</guid>
      <description>I use this setup, along with my bike to work from wherever I want.
It does kind of turn heads, and I&amp;rsquo;m aware it may look a little &amp;lsquo;over the top&amp;rsquo; - but it&amp;rsquo;s a very useful setup for me, keeps me healthy, and fits all my requirements.
Hercules DG400BB Laptop Stand w/ Bag - this portable laptop stand is very sturdy and is designed for mobile DJ use. I find it is excellent in all situations, not just DJ use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 02:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/my-home-network/</guid>
      <description>I have a fibre to the house 2Gb/sec connection provided by BRSK, who I really recommend. My home network routes at around 2-4gbit/sec between 10gbit/sec DAC fibre connected hosts, and around 2gbit/sec via CAT8 for Thunderbolt 2.5Ggbit/sec laptop network interfaces. We two Ubiquiti wireless APs in a mesh configuration, with seperate SSIDs for 2Ghz, 5Ghz, guest and IOT networks. The guest and IOT networks are isolated from everything else. I use a Mikrotik router which hosts an iperf3 docker container for network testing I have a Google smart home setup with 2x Google Home Mini speakers, 1x Google Home Hub (1st) gen, 1x Google Doorbell, 1x Google Nest Smoke Alarm, 1x Google Nest Thermostat, and 2x Google Nest Cameras.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Media and Gaming Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-gaming-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 19:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/my-gaming-setup/</guid>
      <description>Gaming Blog Please visit my separate gaming blog for reviews of games I&amp;rsquo;ve played. It&amp;rsquo;s at https://davidcraddock.games
Media PC 12th Gen i7 CPU 32GB DDR4 RAM 1x NVme M.2 SSD 1TB (system) 1x 1TB SSD 1x 500GB SSD 1x 2.5 TB HDD (storage) 3x Logitech C920 Webcams (for streaming) 1x Logitech C270 Webcam (for video calls) 1x Nvidia 4070 GPU 10Gb/sec fibre card connected to my 10Gb/sec Mikrotik switch 2x Libredrive flashed LG-WH16NS40 multi-disk optical drivers for ripping Blu-rays, CDs, DVDs and any optical disk with MakeMKV and games for my Plex server and emulators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Work Computer</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-work-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 23:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/my-work-computer/</guid>
      <description>This is my work from home setup. I work from home every work day. I use the following equipment:
HDMI, network cables and and USB hookups for 2 additional laptops if needed HDMI Switcher USB Switcher IKEA Motorized Standing Desk Benq 32&amp;quot; 2560x1440 graphic designers monitor on Amazon Basics extendable desk mount arm Honeywell desk fan Logitech 5.1 surround sound system with 5 speakers and subwoofer Sony WH-1000XM3 Apt-X HD Noise cancelling headphones with an Avantree Oasis Plus Apt-X HD bluetooth transmitter, so I can listen to any of the music devices on noise cancelling headphones Ergonomic book stand for textbooks ThinkStation Xeon workstation/server running the latest Ubuntu Fibreoptic 10Gb/sec DAC cable routed from my ThinkStation server to my personal computer downstairs for fast data transfer KVM switch and full hookup for work laptop Drinks holder Groot from Guardians of the Galaxy Phone holder Johnny Silverhand Plushie from Cyberpunk 2077 Pomodoro timer Standing desk mat for easing long standing experiences XL rocker style wooden balance board XL 360 style wooden balance board Fast Anker USB charger Logi USB headset with noise cancelling microphone Kinesis Freestyle 2 ergonomic keyboard Anker vertical mouse Apple Magic Pad 2 that I&amp;rsquo;ve made work with Ubuntu - I use this in preference to the vertical mouse as I&amp;rsquo;ve found it much more comfortable in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/tutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 22:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/tutoring/</guid>
      <description>Please see my David Craddock - Tutor website for more details of tutoring options I can offer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 16:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/music/</guid>
      <description>I create music and DJ in my free time. I have various music projects on the go at any one time.
My &amp;lsquo;Socialist Synthesis&amp;rsquo; project is an experimental/electronica/ambient/soundscape project:
Summer Sun Highway by Socialist Synthesis
Sound Escapes by Socialist Synthesis
I have released an EP under the &amp;lsquo;Machines Move Mountains&amp;rsquo; project with Ellis Breen. It is experimental/electronica/downtempo:
Unfinished Dreams by Machines Move Mountains
I have released some music under the &amp;lsquo;Concrete Spectre&amp;rsquo; project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/about-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 18:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://davidcraddock.net/about-2/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m David Craddock, I live in Manchester, and have worked in IT and software for the past 20 years, currently as a Principal Software Engineer.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
