<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>DavidCraddock.net</title>
    <link>https://davidcraddock.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DavidCraddock.net</description>
    <image>
      <title>DavidCraddock.net</title>
      <url>https://davidcraddock.net/cover.png</url>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.132.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:15:41 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidcraddock.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mid 2024 Retrospective Update</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2024/08/02/mid-2024-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 23:15:41 +0100</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/mid-2024-update.md</guid> 
      <description>Every year I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing these &amp;lsquo;retrospectives&amp;rsquo;, usually once per year but sometimes a couple of times per year.
Things have changed quite significantly since the last retrospective, and I was in a pensive mood, so I thought I would write a retrospective for half the year.
I finally found a job, with CGI, early in the year, and started in March 2023. Unfortunately, for reasons I&amp;rsquo;m contractually obliged not to get into, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before I was looking for work again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moved From Wp to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2024/07/26/moved-from-wp-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 04:28:43 +0100</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/moved-from-wp-to-hugo.md</guid> 
      <description>I have moved over from wordpress.com that I was using before on DavidCraddock.net to self-hosting using Python&amp;rsquo;s Hugo.
I hope this will be a good move!
A bit of content didn&amp;rsquo;t make it, but most of it, thankfully, did.
I will continue to tidy up bits and pieces as I go along.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Bike</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 22:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=4801</guid> 
      <description>
Decided not to mention the security aspects of my setup on a public page, but trust me, there are many!
Himiway Zebra Electric Mountainbike 2023 Version (road legal, top electric-assisted speed 15mph, max pull 400lbs) 2x official batteries (about 60 miles on a single charge each) 2x battery chargers Two spare tires Spare inner tube Electric fat tire pump Metal tire levers Chain tool Chain cleaner tool MuckOff bike cleaning kit Small first aid kit Compass Himiway fold-out cycle toolkit Energy bars + nuts 2x cycle frame bags Himiway official cargo bag with foldout panniers 2x Rockbros waterproof pannier bags Rockbros Handlebar bag Electric bike horn Bike bell Himiway cycle helmet with front light 4x vaccum thermos 750ml flasks for water All-weather MTB grips for handlebar Fingerless MTB gloves for warmer weather Wraparound anti-glare sun glasses for protection against surface dirt etc Wraparound cycle goggles with different visors Light backpack suitable for cycling Gortex water-resistant high-vis cycle jacket RAM Mounts Quick-release handlebar Mobile Phone holder VEVOR Cycle Bike Cargo Trailer </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Routing for Dave Cave Studio</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2024/04/25/video-routing-for-dave-cave-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 04:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=4694</guid> 
      <description>Here is a quick diagram I mocked up to detail exactly how video routing works in the studio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advice to young people in the UK wanting a career in Tech</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2024/04/23/4683/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 22:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=4683</guid> 
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re currently in high school in the UK and want to be a GOOD and EMPLOYED software engineer.. this is my advice.
Start programming on personal projects right away, and keep it up during your entire working career. Always have something going on in the background. Get into a RUSSELL GROUP university in the UK and take a technical, demanding degree in a computing-related discipline, for example, Physics, Electronic Engineering, Maths, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Mobile Laptop Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-mobile-laptop-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 02:48:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=4413</guid> 
      <description>I use this setup, along with my bike to work from wherever I want.
It does kind of turn heads, and I&amp;rsquo;m aware it may look a little &amp;lsquo;over the top&amp;rsquo; - but it&amp;rsquo;s a very useful setup for me, keeps me healthy, and fits all my requirements.
Hercules DG400BB Laptop Stand w/ Bag - this portable laptop stand is very sturdy and is designed for mobile DJ use. I find it is excellent in all situations, not just DJ use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Acquisition Process for DJ Music</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2024/01/11/music-acquisition-process-for-dj-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 23:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=4348</guid> 
      <description>My music acquisition process for DJ music:
ARM (Automatic Ripping Machine) rips CDs I buy into FLAC form without any interactivity. You just insert a CD into the Linux server, and then it ejects it when it&amp;rsquo;s done. Lidarr downloads FLACs of any tracks of artists I have in my collection, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have their full discography. It does this automatically and silently in the background. Once a day, a cron job imports ARM and Lidarr downloads into my Beets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-home-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 02:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=4287</guid> 
      <description>My home network routes at around 2-4gbit/sec between 10gbit/sec DAC fibre connected hosts, and around 2gbit/sec via CAT8 for Thunderbolt 2.5Ggbit/sec laptop network interfaces. We two Ubiquiti wireless APs in a mesh configuration, with seperate SSIDs for 2Ghz, 5Ghz, guest and IOT networks. The guest and IOT networks are isolated from everything else. I use a Mikrotik router which hosts an iperf3 docker container for network testing I have a home server running Ubuntu Linux that hosts a bunch of services via docker containers, including Pi-Hole for DNS and a Ubiquiti Network Controller.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective for 2023</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2023/11/25/retrospective-for-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 20:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=4226</guid> 
      <description>Every year towards the end of the year, I put together a retrospective of events that have happened over the year - the good, bad and the ugly.
The Bad Most of the year was taken up with treatment for relapsed Hodgkins Lymphoma cancer. After the clinical immunotherapy drug trial finished in Feb 2023, cancer was unfortunately still detected, so it did not completely cure it. I had a further (awful) spell in hospital around March/April where my Hickman line became infected and I had a severe mental health episode, probably caused by the strong antibiotics being pumped through my system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest Remote Guitar Lesson Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2023/09/22/latest-remote-guitar-lesson-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 16:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=4053</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having online guitar lessons with my friend Jon.
After a while we have got things down to a setup that seems to work remotely.
I have an Epiphone Les Paul Vintage Edition electric guitar, and a Marshall MG15G Practice Amp. I use a headphone splitter cable to plug into the Marshall&amp;rsquo;s headphone out socket, which splits the audio into left and right channels, and a 3.5mm to phono mono cable plugged into the headphone splitter that runs to my audio interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Media and Gaming Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-gaming-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 19:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=3856</guid> 
      <description>Media PC I use this mainly as a general purpose PC, and for streaming on Twitch. I also use it for video editing, adding animations, animated gifs, anything visual etc and audio editing for processing mixcloud uploads. I also use it to rip Blu-rays for my Plex server, and to watch movies and listen to music on as it has my studio EQ calibrated Sonorworks SoundID Reference profiles.
12th Gen i7 CPU 32GB DDR4 RAM 1x NVme M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical Drive Cleaners and Home Entertainment Test Tools</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2023/02/23/optical-drive-cleaners-and-home-entertainment-test-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3617</guid> 
      <description>If you are still using optical discs, e.g. CDs or Blu-rays, in music, video or games, then you are in the minority these days. Downloads and streaming have become the norm, which means 1) A lot less discs are being produced 2) A lot less optical drives are being produced.
Because a lot less optical drives are being produced, we can imagine a time in the future when the only optical drives you can buy, are second-hand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books that have changed the way I see the practice of Software Engineering</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2023/01/19/books-that-have-changed-the-way-i-see-the-practice-of-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 09:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3531</guid> 
      <description>The Mythical Man Month and other Essays - Fred Brooks - Read it as part of my university degree. A lot of good sense. I can&amp;rsquo;t believe there are people out there in charge of software projects that haven&amp;rsquo;t read this book, or think it somehow doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply anymore, but unfortunately, it seems quite common. -
[Read reviews on Good Reads] The Cathedral and the Bazaar - Eric S Raymound - One of the first books I read on software development process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Retrospective on 2022</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/12/23/my-personal-retrospective-on-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 23:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3472</guid> 
      <description>Every year (when I remember) I do an end-of-year summary to outline what has been going on in my life. I’ve been doing this for a few years now, and it’s a great way to look back on the year and see has happened.
The Bad: The main bad news of the year is that, contrary to expectations, my Hodgkins Lymphoma cancer was detected again around April after the initial chemotherapy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Work Computer</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/my-work-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 23:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=3423</guid> 
      <description>This is my work from home setup. I work from home every work day. I use the following equipment:
HDMI, network cables and and USB hookups for 2 additional laptops if needed HDMI Switcher USB Switcher IKEA Motorized Standing Desk Benq 32&amp;quot; 2560x1440 graphic designers monitor on Amazon Basics extendable desk mount arm Pro-Ject Record Player Honeywell desk fan Logitech 5.1 surround sound system with 5 speakers and subwoofer Sony WH-1000XM3 Apt-X HD Noise cancelling headphones with an Avantree Oasis Plus Apt-X HD bluetooth transmitter, so I can listen to any of the music devices on noise cancelling headphones Ergonomic book stand for textbooks ThinkStation Xeon workstation/server running the latest Ubuntu Fibreoptic 10Gb/sec DAC cable routed from my ThinkStation server to my personal computer downstairs for fast data transfer 1GB/sec ethernet cable and gigabit switch running downstairs for general internet KVM switch and full hookup for work laptop Drinks holder Groot from Guardians of the Galaxy Phone holder Johnny Silverhand Plushie from Cyberpunk 2077 Pomodoro timer Standing desk mat for easing long standing experiences XL rocker style wooden balance board XL 360 style wooden balance board Fast Anker USB charger Logi USB headset with noise cancelling microphone Kinesis Freestyle 2 ergonomic keyboard Anker vertical mouse Apple Magic Pad 2 that I&amp;rsquo;ve made work with Ubuntu - I use this in preference to the vertical mouse as I&amp;rsquo;ve found it much more comfortable in most cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Working from Home</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/10/18/tips-for-working-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 17:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3317</guid> 
      <description>I have been working from home, the majority of the time, for over 5 years. It took a lot of adjustment, and I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% adjusted, but if you want to undertake this, then these are my tips.
Note that a big part of the benefit from working from home is the total flexibility in work environment, so these are only tips that work for me - they might not work for you!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PSP Preset for Handbrake for transcoding video files into a PSP compatible format</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/10/16/psp-preset-for-handbrake-for-transcoding-video-files-into-a-psp-compatible-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3304</guid> 
      <description>This is based off of the 2021 Reddit post here: https://www.reddit.com/r/PSP/comments/kcx4ei/tutorial_convert_most_video_formats_to/
I am using it with Handbrake 1.5.1. You can import it into your Handbrake via &amp;ldquo;Preset -&amp;gt; File Import&amp;rdquo;.
Download PSP Handbrake Preset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Current State of UK Politics</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/29/the-current-state-of-uk-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 04:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3276</guid> 
      <description>For years, UK politics has become more right-wing, popularist, and presidential.
Right-wing, because the Conservatives have been in power for over 10 years, and have had the opportunity to implement most of their ideological policies, which we see at the moment highlighted to an extreme with Liz Truss gearing up to emulate Thatcher on almost every level.
Popularist, because the Conservatives have implemented policies designed to appease the populations feelings, rather than those based on factual positive outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tips for new Ubuntu Users</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/29/tips-for-new-ubuntu-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3270</guid> 
      <description>Here are some extra tips if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting started out on Ubuntu.
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through the UI to shut down or reboot your computer. You can do it from the command line. The commands are:
sudo reboot # to reboot sudo poweroff # to shut down and power off the computer You can get a lot more information on your computers startup and shutdown sequences by removing the default Ubuntu splash screen that obscures this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Twitch DJ Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/27/current-dj-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 02:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3255</guid> 
      <description>Click to view full diagram
Hardware 2 x Reloop 8000mk2 turntables Roland 707m Mixer and DJ Controller 2015 Macbook Pro (DJ Laptop) SoundSwitch USB -&amp;gt; DMX interface, attached to broadcast PC Beatstep MIDI Controller mapped for controlling SoundSwitch, attached to broadcast PC Vestax VCM-600 MIDI Controller used for controlling Resolume, attached to broadcast PC AKAI LPD8 MIDI Controller used for controlling Serato&amp;rsquo;s FX, attached to DJ laptop Rode Soundcaster Pro microphone used as a DJ mic 4 x Phillips Hue Colour Bulbs in lamps Phillips Hue Lightstrip Behringer UMC1820 Sound Interface connected to broadcast PC, attached to broadcast PC 2 x Logitech C920 Cameras used for capturing video for streaming, attached to broadcast PC Software SoundSwitch lighting software running on broadcast PC Resolume Avenue running on broadcast PC Streamlabs OBS running on broadcast PC Serato DJ Pro software running on DJ laptop </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Drive Backup using Rclone</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/24/google-drive-backup-using-rclone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 17:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3249</guid> 
      <description>For 8 TB of data storage on Google Drive, plus my own Google organization, I am paying £30/month, which is a pretty good deal.
I wanted to use this space for backing up my NAS, but it was proving difficult. The program I was recommended for Linux backup, Duplicati, was not the best for this purpose. My backup runs would not complete, they would be slow, and full of syncing errors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Network September 2022</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/08/home-network-september-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 09:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3219</guid> 
      <description>I had planned a different network toplogy for sure, but this is my current setup and it seems to work well:
I was not able to implement connection load balancing using the Miktrotik router. It was just too complicated and didn&amp;rsquo;t work reliably enough. My current network is a gigabit network across all areas, so every PC has gigabit cables, switch and so on. I either have plugged in my Virgin Media 1000mb/50mbs internet connection or my BRSK fibre 900mb/900mb connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Job Requirements</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/09/01/my-ideal-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 21:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3203</guid> 
      <description>I have nearly 20 years experience, so my skill-set is in high demand from all sorts of different organisations. If I were looking for a job, then these would be my priorities:
Understanding of medical appointments - My situation is that I currently have cancer. Although it&amp;rsquo;s recommended I work, some of my time will be spent in medical appointments at the hospital that is 15 mins walk away from me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Tracking</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/08/18/sleep-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 19:58:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3173</guid> 
      <description>I really like my Withings Mattress-Based Sleep Tracker.
I keep unusual sleeping hours a lot of the time, as I&amp;rsquo;m undergoing treatment, and a lot of the medication I&amp;rsquo;m taking effect my sleep. Even when I&amp;rsquo;m relatively healthy, some of the medication I&amp;rsquo;m on for a long-term condition also affects my sleep.
What&amp;rsquo;s more, I enjoy a non-standard sleeping schedule. I find I get more work done in the early morning or late at night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Game Collecting</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/08/09/digital-game-collecting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 02:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3158</guid> 
      <description>I have a relatively obscure hobby - I collect digital video games. Quite a few people collect physical games, but I like the advantages of having a large library of gaming options which are just a download away.
Like a lot of collectors, I have more games than I have actually played, or probably will do in my lifetime. I mostly get them via discounted bundles such as HumbleBundle.com, so I rarely play full price for them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Network Design 28/7/22</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/07/28/home-network-design-28-7-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:57:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3139</guid> 
      <description>Now that I actually have the internet connectivity being installed to make use of it, I am getting my home network design a bit more finished.
Components:
Virgin Hub providing a 1100/50mbps connection BetterInternet Fibre Hub providing a 900/900mbps connection Raspberry Pi 3 running Pi-Hole DNS MikroTik CRS309-1G-8S+IN Cloud Router Switch 4 x SFP+10Gb SFP+ RJ45 Copper Modules CAT8 30M Outdoor Cable to connect the studio to the study Short run CAT7 Patch Cables Windows 11 Studio PC with 10GB/sec SFP+ Port ThinkStation Server with twin 10GB/sec SFP+ Ports and separate gigabit NIC 3x LinkSys 3200WRT Routers in wireless repeater mode, creating a 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIDI Routing for Home Studio</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/06/19/midi-routing-for-home-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 03:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3084</guid> 
      <description>I have had this knowledge in my head for a long time now and thought it would be better to write a diagram to explain the current setup for my MIDI routing.
I use MIDI routing one way - MIDI OUT - from my UMC1820 sound interface.
I have two keyboard controllers, one next to my computer, and one next to my Eurorack, that are attached via USB to my computer which I route the notes via Ableton to the MIDI out of the UMC1820 interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Network Design</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/05/15/home-network-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 23:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3029</guid> 
      <description>Did some network design for my home network. This will ensure that my new Virgin Media 1100mbps/50mps speed is fully utilised without any bottlenecks and will futureproof things up to at least 2.5Gbs/speed connections.
I should be able to load balance both internet connections to utilise them both simultaniously in the future, but for now I want to be able to get greater than 1000mbit/s speed on a single device otherwise there is not much point in speed increases past 1000mbits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DJ Setup 2/5/22</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/05/02/dj-setup-2-5-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=3000</guid> 
      <description>This is my current DJ setup that I use for Twitch streaming mainly.
2x Reloop RL-8000mk2 turntables. 2x Serato ‘Butter Rug’ Slipmats. 2x Concorde Mk2 Digital carts. Numark NDX500 CDJ which I use for playing CDs, and as a Serato Controller as it has Serato Integration. Roland DJ-707m controller. Sennheiser HD-25 headphones. Rode Procaster mic with mic boom, pop shield and cage. t.bone MB 88U mic with table stand that I use as a guest microphone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Tools I use for my Media Collection</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/03/16/video-tools-i-use-for-my-media-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2968</guid> 
      <description>I use and recommend the following software for Windows. They&amp;rsquo;re all quite easy to use. The paid software all have lifetime subscriptions, which are worth it because you need the latest updates in this area.
Aiseesoft Blu-ray Player: (for playing Blu-Rays) (paid) https://www.aiseesoft.com/blu-ray-player/
Easyfab Lossless Copy: (for ripping Blu-Rays, also works for DVDs) (paid) https://www.easefab.com/losslesscopy/
VLC: (for playing ripped copies) (free) https://www.videolan.org/
Handbrake: (for converting between different video formats and compressing video) (free) https://handbrake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using VIM as a Word Processor</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/03/08/using-vim-as-a-word-processor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2958</guid> 
      <description>It may surprise some people to learn that I don&amp;rsquo;t use a word processor to write pure text any more, and haven&amp;rsquo;t for several months. I still have a subscription to Microsoft Office 365, and probably will as long as recruiters and offices around the world still pay the MS tax.
I have created my own custom writing environment in my favourite text editor, VIM. This may sound like an absolutely foolish thing to do to anyone who knows VIM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DJ Setup 03/03/2022</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/03/03/dj-setup-03-03-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 01:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2933</guid> 
      <description>This is my current DJ setup with the following components:
Decks 1 and 2 - 2x Reloop 8000mk2 Vinyl Turntables with Serato intergration Deck 3 - Numark NDX500 CDJ with Serato Integration Deck 4 - Roland 707m Serato Controller and Mixer using its internal drum machine as a deck Behringer TB-303 Clone fed into the Aux input of the Roland 707m Controller Pioneer EFX-1000 DJ FX Unit placed between the master out of the 707m controller and the input of the sound interface on the broadcasting PC Reloop Neon Serato Controller used to control the Serato DJ Pro sampler Rode Procaster Microphone (not shown in diagram) fed to the Mic 1 channel on the 707m Controller as the main microphone for me while DJing t.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with Jenkinsfiles in VIM</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/02/19/working-with-jenkinsfiles-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 05:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2917</guid> 
      <description>Using Jenkinsfiles in repositories for declarative pipelines, which is an example as infrastructure as code, is absolutely the right thing to do, in my opinion.
However the tooling for debugging and error checking Jenkinsfiles is currently quite difficult.
Setup Jenkinsfile linter First of all you need to make sure to be able to access the Jenkinsfile linter. This linter is processed on the Jenkins server itself, unusually. There is a configuration option that requires adminstrator access to the Jenkins server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Story in Tech</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/02/13/my-story-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 08:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2901</guid> 
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write here a bit about how I got into technology and how my career has progressed for those people wanting to get into technology.
I was lucky enough to be born in a supportive home to good parents. My father was an early entrant into the world of computing, and my birth certificate records his profession as a &amp;lsquo;Computer Science Lecturer&amp;rsquo;, which was very rare at the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy and Security methods I use</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/01/14/privacy-and-security-methods-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 06:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2880</guid> 
      <description>Ever since I worked at an internet marketing company on an advertising analytics platform, I have realised that I don&amp;rsquo;t want my personal internet browsing tracked, monetised, influenced, and sold to the highest bidder. These are the steps that I have taken to reduce (you can never totally eliminate) this process.
Pi-Hole DNS This is a DNS server installed on a Raspberry Pi on my local home network. I have all the internet traffic going through my Virgin Media router filtered through this DNS server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Persuit of Happiness and the Hill-Climbing Problem</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/01/07/the-persuit-of-happiness-and-the-hill-climbing-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 05:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2867</guid> 
      <description>It seems that for a lot of people, perhaps the vast majority, they cannot expect to be 100% happy all the time. Even those incredibly successful celebrities and incredibly rich CEOs and politicians are not happy 100% of the time.
So is it a good idea to seek 100% happiness right away? Or should we always try and select the &amp;rsquo;least worst&amp;rsquo; situation? If we keep making progress and optimse our happiness levels through constantly selecting the &amp;rsquo;least worst&amp;rsquo; situation whenever we have a descision then it seems to me we will maximise our happiness potential in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective on 2021</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2022/01/01/retrospective-on-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:58:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2849</guid> 
      <description>Well, 2021 has been a bit of a downer in a number of ways. There has been some upsides though.
I spent the first part of 2021 burned out, as in - totally burned out - of my career and really needing a break. This affected my work. It turns out that unknown to me at the time, I had cancer, Hodgkins Lymophoma, and a lot of my lack of energy and generally feeling awful was down to a large tumor that had been growing my chest for some time and was pressing down on my heart and lungs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Enlightenment window manager on Ubuntu 21.10</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/11/18/setting-up-enlightenment-window-manager-on-ubuntu-21-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 08:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2829</guid> 
      <description>Enlightenment is a very underrated window manager choice, in my opinion. It still looks very pretty and is very configurable. There is a packaging bug with the latest version of Enlightement in the 21.10 repo which means it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly. The fix is to set the suid bit on the &amp;rsquo;enlightenment_system&amp;rsquo; binary. So:
sudo apt install enlightenment sudo find /usr/lib -type f -name enlightenment_system -exec sudo chmod 4755 {} \; Log out of Ubuntu Click the settings cog in the bottom right to change your Window manager to enlightenment Log on and the settings wizard will help you configure Enlightenment </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Simple Commandline Git Workflow</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/10/21/my-simple-commandline-git-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 16:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2755</guid> 
      <description>This is a simple description of how I work 99% of the time, as I am a simpleton. Origin/main is the new origin/master for future repositories, I just note both here for completeness because I use origin master for a lot of current repos.
I first make sure I am uptodate on origin/master or origin/main by git pulling. git checkout origin master git pull origin master I start making changes to the local copy on my local machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix Plex Media Servers &#39;Various Artists&#39; problem using Beets.io and other tools</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/09/21/how-to-fix-plex-media-servers-various-artists-problem-using-beets-io-and-other-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 22:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2720</guid> 
      <description>The Problem As of the day of posting, Plex Media Server has a suboptimal handling of Various Artists compilations. Unless you follow BOTH of these rules, described clearly on the Plex support here under &amp;lsquo;Various Artists&amp;rsquo;, then they won&amp;rsquo;t appear collected under a particular album, they will be spread out filed under the different artists that created them. I think it should only require one of these rules, but it is not up to me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My PSP Entertainment System for 2021!</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/08/07/my-psp-entertainment-system-for-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 19:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2641</guid> 
      <description>I have recently been in hospital and been diagnosed with a condition that might mean I need to return quite a bit, at least in the short term. When I was in hospital I was struck by the fact that there were very long periods of waiting and it was easy to get very bored and quite dejected just sitting in a hospital bed.
Also there is not a lot of room for laptops, tablets and other things – you really don’t get a lot of space by your bed usually to store large items and they are not practical most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Twitch DJ Promo Mix Videos</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/06/13/making-twitch-dj-promo-mix-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 20:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2595</guid> 
      <description>Sometimes as a DJ you may want to reconstruct the Twitch stream you have streamed into a video format to send to other people, for promotional purposes, or just to have a record of what you&amp;rsquo;ve done. Twitch makes this difficult though, as it mutes copyrighted music in the video it records for your Twitch stream. Also, when you download this video, it does not include the chat log, so any attempts at reconstruction are without the chat, so it looks like the DJ is just talking to him/herself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Navidrome on a RPI3 to host my music collection for DJing so I can listen between sets</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/06/09/using-navidrome-on-a-rpi3-to-host-my-music-collection-for-djing-so-i-can-listen-between-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2584</guid> 
      <description>As a DJ it is important to listen to the music in your collection so you get an idea of what would work in particular sets, and you have a memory of how the tracks progress. So I decided to host a Spotify like service in my house so I could listen to my 500GB+ DJ music library. Navidrome (free open source software from https://navidrome.org) is running on the Raspberry Pi 3 which is under my desk via a wired connection with it&amp;rsquo;s own http://navidrome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proper Care and Operation of Vinyl Turntables for DJs</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/06/01/2552/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 23:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2552</guid> 
      <description>Setup your new Turntable Follow this and only this guide. This is the best vinyl setup video on the internet as of 2021:
[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WM-aIDwfrhc&amp;amp;w=560&amp;amp;h=315]
A lot of DJ turntables are based on Technics OEM clones, and so you will need to set the tonearm height, which is the only thing not covered by the above video:
[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SYScinvkrrM]
The Basics Once you&amp;rsquo;ve setup your turntable:
Should go without saying that I always use a velvet dust brush on my records just before I play them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lighting and Camera Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/05/11/lighting-and-camera-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 03:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2526</guid> 
      <description>Light Sources: Phillips Hue Colour Lamp (top right) Phillips Hue Colour Lamp (Middle) Phillips Hue Colour Lamp (Bottom) Phillips Hue Lightstrip &amp;ldquo;DJ David Craddock&amp;rdquo; white illuminated sign &amp;ldquo;Live on Air&amp;rdquo; blue sign Laser (green or red laser wash) Revolving disco balls Dark Music Lighting Settings For Phillips Hue sources I use Hue Sync on my broadcast PC which syncs the lights in time with the music. I will use different palletes depending on the event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organising Huge Music Libraries for use with Serato DJ Pro</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/05/05/organising-huge-music-libraries-with-serato/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 21:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2490</guid> 
      <description>Updated: 25-11-22
My music library is around 24k files, mostly FLAC and some 320kbps MP3s. I use the following tools to organise my music library:
Acquisition: dbPoweramp CD Ripper - https://www.dbpoweramp.com/cd-ripper.htm Bandcamp Collection Downloader - https://github.com/Ezwen/bandcamp-collection-downloader Soulseek - http://www.slsknet.org Tagging and Metadata: Beets - https://beets.io Mixed In Key - https://mixedinkey.com Lexicon https://www.lexicondj.com/ Backup and sync: Robocopy - comes free with Windows 10. Documentation: https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/administration/windows-commands/robocopy Google Drive Rsync
Searching: Everything Search - https://voidtools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolume MIDI Control in my Twitch DJing Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/04/26/resolume-midi-control-in-my-twitch-djing-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2477</guid> 
      <description>I have retired the Novation SL Zero Mk1 MIDI controller that was causing me a lot of grief when I was running Resolume and Ableton Live at the same time, as its Automap functionality was locking on to the Ableton Live mixer in session view now and then, and so, sometimes, when I thought I was controlling Resolumes visual FX, I was actually changing the volume faders in my DJ mix.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Serato DJ Pro DVS/Ableton Live DJ setup (21/4/21)</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/04/08/dj-setup-8-4-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 03:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2424</guid> 
      <description>I recently found a good price on a Vestax VCM-600 controller. It is a specially made MIDI controller for Ableton Live, with the same build quality as a DJ mixer. It allows for control over 6 channels in the Ableton Live &amp;lsquo;session&amp;rsquo; view, which is arranged similarly to a mixing console. It also adds dozens of MIDI mappable DJ controls such as the traditional Hi, Mid and Lo EQs, a crossfader, a filter control, control over a lot of Ableton FX, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2020 Retrospective – Wow, what a year!</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/03/04/2020-retrospective-wow-what-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 19:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2387</guid> 
      <description>I think, for obvious reasons, 2020 has been a year that no-one could really have expected. With COVID-19 and lockdown, a lot of things have changed, both in my life, in everyone&amp;rsquo;s lives, and in the workplace.
My online DJing setup
Things that went well I changed medication around March 2020 which has resulted in significant weight loss, as expected. The previous medication was making me put on and retain weight even when I was eating very very little.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26/2/2021 DJ Setup with Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/02/26/26-2-2021-dj-setup-with-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 17:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2373</guid> 
      <description>After the last post I have added Ableton Live and my Eurorack modular to my DJ setup, with a master clock being sent via MIDI cables from my Roland TR8 drum machine that syncs with Ableton. The drum machine also can be used creatively for drum fills etc.
I hope these two diagrams explain my setup adequately - sometimes a picture is worth a thousand words! The &amp;lsquo;actor&amp;rsquo; is me - I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way to change that on http://draw.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DJ Books: Reviewed</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/02/18/dj-books-reviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 16:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2362</guid> 
      <description>The classic!
Yes! Some people actually write and read BOOKS on DJing. As if YouTube wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Well it can be enough.. but YouTube is also a cess pit of rubbish information, and at least a book has a better chance of being properly edited and reviewed. Also reading a book makes you more intellectual. Which is utterly true.
So. I have been reading through these DJing books to see if they could teach me something I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about DJing after over 10 years doing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twitch Streaming Technical Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/02/14/twitch-dj-streaming-technical-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 23:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2342</guid> 
      <description>I thought I’d write a bit here about my Twitch DJing setup and some of the hardware and software I’m using. Twitch streaming has become very popular over the lockdown period, and I think people might be interested in how I have configured my stream. Something that seperates my stream from anyone else I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on Twitch is that is that I do live vinyl DJing AND live VJing at the same time on my stream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David’s Guide to The News</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2021/01/08/davids-guide-to-the-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 08:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1843</guid> 
      <description>Journalism has deteriorated to a huge degree in the online age. A lot of articles and video content are one-sided short ‘clickbait’ – short messages designed to trigger an extreme emotional reaction. ALMOST ALL journalism is like this these days, it doesn’t matter if you have a highly established news network you have been trusting for decades, they have all had to adopt this low-quality strategy due to the ultra-competitive and dire financial situation that all news reporting finds itself in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finally my 27U Eurorack is complete!</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2020/12/11/finally-my-27u-eurorack-is-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 22:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2288</guid> 
      <description>The three sections Left 9U section Right 9U section Middle 9U section So.. finally my 27U Eurorack modular synthesiser is complete. I have filled up the third - and surely last, as there is no more room in the studio! - case. I started this Eurorack modular in 2015.. so I am glad it is all complete now. I put in a small amount nearly every month for new modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ivy Bridge 2011 PCs are still useful today</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2020/10/13/ivy-bridge-2011-pcs-are-still-useful-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2243</guid> 
      <description>In our house, seperate to my main PC (see the tab above) we still have two Ivy Bridge-based PCs:
Conny&amp;rsquo;s PC
i7-3770K 16GB DDR3 RAM Nvidea Radeon 970 Graphics Card 250 GB SSD Windows 10 My wife uses this as her main PC, and plays quite a few games with it. For a CPU and motherboard that I put together in 2011 or so, I am quite amazed it still runs adequetely!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutoring</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/tutoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 22:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?page_id=2232</guid> 
      <description>Please see my David Craddock - Tutor website for more details of tutoring options I can offer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studio Setup in 2020</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2020/01/30/studio-setup-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 14:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2127</guid> 
      <description>I have made some considerable modifications to my modular since my last post. I have a 4-voice polyphony setup now with multiple voice Osc, VCA, Envelope and MIDI-CV modules, allowing me to experiment with polyphony voicing.
Elsewhere, I have added an Access Virus C synthesizer to my studio, and now have rack-mounted Behringer Model D and Emu Orbit 9090 synthesizers. I have also upgraded to Ableton 10 and use NI&amp;rsquo;s Komplete suite including Massive X, plus TAL-NO-UX Juno 106 softsynth, Sylenth1 and others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Retrospective for Years 2016-19</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2019/03/30/a-retrospective-for-years-2016-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 23:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=2034</guid> 
      <description>I thought I&amp;rsquo;d update my blog to reflect recent changes in my life, and review what was good and bad about them, as I was doing before.
The &amp;ldquo;Not Awesome&amp;rdquo;
My overall health level has got a bit worse over the years. I have had limited success in losing weight. I was going for regular walks nearly every week with a friend of mine, but that has stopped lately. I find it difficult exercising while living in a city, as my favourite activity for excercising is walking, and there are not a huge amount of pleasent walking oppertunities around my area.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Cinema Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2018/05/20/home-cinema-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1993</guid> 
      <description>I have been gradually adding parts to my PC so that it functions better for watching movies and gaming. Here are the components that I have used:
Monitor – BenQ EX3501R 35″ Ultra WQHD Curved Monitor This monitor is great for watching movies and gaming as it is ultra-wide at an aspect radio of 21:9, 3440x1440, a VA panel with high contrast, and the monitor is slightly curved so that you get a cinematic experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finished Eurorack</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/06/16/finished-eurorack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1940</guid> 
      <description>Finally I have finished my Eurorack synthesiser! And I know many people say that &amp;lsquo;Euroracks are never finished&amp;rsquo; but this one absolutely has to be, for financial reasons. I think that I have got to a place where I have every major feature common in most synthesisers, but in a modular instrument format. It is a great place to learn about different synthesis techniques.
[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;1945&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo;]
This is the layout on Modulargrid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Node.js HTTPS server with self-signed certificate creation on openssl 0.9.8zh with node.js 7.10.0</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/05/10/node-js-https-server-with-self-signed-certificate-creation-on-openssl-0-9-8zh-with-node-js-7-10-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 13:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1923</guid> 
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a concise guide to setting this up quickly so thought it was worth a post. To quickly get something working and create a https server using the above versions of openssl and node.js, do the following:
Generate self-signed server certificate with no password sudo openssl req -x509 -newkey rsa:2048 -keyout ./csr.pem -out server.crt -days 3001 -nodes Use this node.js code to setup a server quickly const https = require(&#39;https&#39;); const fs = require(&#39;fs&#39;); const options = { key: fs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finished Planning My Eurorack Modular Synthesizer</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/04/16/finished-planning-my-eurorack-modular-synthesizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 21:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1865</guid> 
      <description>In January 2015 I put in an order for my first Eurorack case. Little did I know that I would end up filling that case and buying a larger one. Finally, 2 years and 3 months later, I have nearly finished assembling what will be the complete Eurorack. I have been buying a module or two per month, researching what I need and playing a lot with what I have got already to find out its limitations and areas for possible expansion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals for 2017</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/02/27/goals-for-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 14:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1847</guid> 
      <description>Looking at my past posts, you may notice that I didn&amp;rsquo;t set myself any goals for 2016. Looking back, this was a mistake, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to remedy this by setting some for 2017.
Goals:
Lose a significant amount of weight - this is very important for health reasons. Study maths courses - I intend to sign up for some maths courses at the OU. This will improve my mathematical knowledge, allowing for further study in subjects I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, plus allow me to work in more mathematically-heavy careers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studio Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/02/11/studio-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1844</guid> 
      <description>This is my current studio setup.
I have the following gear:
Eurorack 9U case Eurorack 6U case KORG MS20 Mini Synth Roland TB3 Synth AY3 Chiptune Synth Roland A500-PRO Keyboard Controller Nord Drum Synth Macbook Pro with Ableton Live 9 Suite MIDI.OCD Polyphonic MIDI-&amp;gt;CV Converter Samson Patchbay
I am looking to sell my Acces Virus A and concentrate on filling up the remaining Eurorack case holes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Wordpress.com</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2017/01/30/switching-to-wordpress-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 07:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/?p=1830</guid> 
      <description>I am currently moving the blog, which was formerly hosted on Dreamhost, to Wordpress.com hosting. Most of the content is moved over already, I have to go through all the posts and tidy up the references, relink the images etc. Hopefully I will get around to this shortly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 17:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.wordpress.com/?page_id=3</guid> 
      <description>[contact-form][contact-field label=&amp;ldquo;Name&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; required=&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;/][contact-field label=&amp;ldquo;Email&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;email&amp;rdquo; required=&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;/][contact-field label=&amp;ldquo;Website&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;url&amp;rdquo;/][contact-field label=&amp;ldquo;Comment&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;textarea&amp;rdquo; required=&amp;ldquo;1&amp;rdquo;/][/contact-form]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Workflow 2017</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/12/03/music-workflow-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 20:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1779</guid> 
      <description>In 2017 I want to build a relatively static hardware-based workflow. This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen: The components are:
Roland A-500PRO keyboard controller - https://www.roland.com/global/products/a-500pro/ Arpie MIDI Arpeggiator - https://www.tindie.com/products/hotchk155/arpie-midi-arpeggiator-kit/ CV.OCD Midi -&amp;gt; CV Convertor - https://www.tindie.com/products/hotchk155/cvocd-a-super-flexible-midi-to-cv-box/ KORG MS20 Semi-Modular Mini Synth Eurorack - https://www.modulargrid.net/e/racks/view/350623 Nord Drum Semi-Modular Drum Module - http://www.nordkeyboards.com/products/nord-drum Stereo Memory Man with Hazarai (Reverb/Echo Pedal) - http://www.ehx.com/products/stereo-memory-man-with-hazarai Focusrite Saffire Pro 24 Audio Interface - https://us.focusrite.com/firewire-audio-interfaces/saffire-pro-24 Ableton Push Controller (MK1) - https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Music-Making Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/11/16/current-music-making-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 17:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1768</guid> 
      <description>With my current setup, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make as much music &amp;lsquo;out of the box&amp;rsquo; as possible, away from the computer as I find it more fun.
Synths: KORG Minilogue: I use this for a keyboard controller, and I use the 16 step sequencer to run simple sequences. It connects to the PC via USB and has MIDI output. I can also use this as a synthesizer its own right, it&amp;rsquo;s good for backing chords and pads.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Narrative-Led PC Games</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/09/05/narrative-led-pc-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 17:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1751</guid> 
      <description>When I first started getting into computer roleplaying games in the 90s/00s I remember playing the Infinity Engine games by Bioware and Black Isle, such as Baldur’s Gate 2, the original Fallout games, and of course Planescape: Torment. It was the quality of writing that drew me in and took me to another world, the graphics were just a background setting to that writing.
Somewhere in the 2000s RPGs became more action orientated and prioritised mechanics and visual appeal and combat over branching stories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eurorack 2016</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/04/16/eurorack-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 20:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1737</guid> 
      <description>So.. the problem, as so many people have said, with getting into building a Eurorack modular synthesizer is that it becomes addictive, and you inevitably spend more than you can really afford. That said.. I now have a great fully customised synthesiser for what I want to do :) The layout is:
Top shelf: 3 oscilators and noise generator in the top left, 4 VCAs and S&amp;amp;H and Ring Mod sections in the mid center, LFOs in the top right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OSX Fish Functions to open Chrome from the Shell</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/04/04/osx-fish-functions-to-open-chrome-from-the-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 11:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1734</guid> 
      <description>These functions are quite handy, and allow you to do things such as copy and paste errors and google for them without having to manually open a browser. You have to enclose arguments to both functions in single quotes, e.g. &amp;lsquo;chrome &amp;lsquo;http://www.google.co.uk&amp;rsquo; and google &amp;lsquo;one two three four&amp;rsquo;. You should add these to your config file at ~/.config/fish/config.fish and make sure Google Chrome is already installed.
[code language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;] function chrome /usr/bin/open -a &amp;lsquo;/Applications/Google Chrome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My vIM Configuration</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/03/26/my-vim-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 04:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1727</guid> 
      <description>I use a heavily customised setup for vIM, the text editor that annoys me the least in ~30 years of using a computer. You can see my exact setup in my dotfiles repo on github, https://github.com/wordswords/-.
Here are the plugins I use:
ConqueTerm - Opens a shell window inside vIM, allowing you to have a REPL environment within vIM. NERDTree - A filetree plugin that you can see on the left of the window above.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with Fish Shell, ffmpeg, MP4Box and sox to generate audio files</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/03/08/working-with-fish-shell-ffmpeg-mp4box-and-sox-to-generate-audio-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1711</guid> 
      <description>More adventures with Fish shell. I have scripted the generation of a bunch of test asset audio files in mp4 format suitable for dash streaming. I have used the audio file commandline tools ffmepg MP4Box and sox in this script, they are pretty powerful and worth installing via homebrew on OSX.
Thoughts: I think that instead of quoting you can just output $variable, which is probably better coding style. I&amp;rsquo;m still working out good way to return variables from functions, it seems that you need to echo out the output and that gets picked up by the calling function, which is a bit messy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio Routing for my PC</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/02/06/audio-routing-for-my-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 08:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1693</guid> 
      <description>For my own benefit as much as anyone elses, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d document my PC audio setup. I have two soundcards and two sets of speakers, one surround soundcard and speaker set for gaming and watching surround sound movies, and one audio interface linked up to my studio monitor speakers for music production. I also have a Digi 002 mixer which I use to mix in the outputs from my synthesisers to my recording interface.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fish Shell Scripting</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/02/02/fish-shell-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 17:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1685</guid> 
      <description>A few months ago I switched across from Bash onto the Fish shell, on my main development machine. I can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of its fast autosuggestions and its sane scripting language. Compared to Bash it is very fun to use.
Today I wrote a script to automate the backup of my development workspace onto a private bitbucket account. Bitbucket is good because it allows unlimited private repositories, but it caps the size of these repos at 2GB max, with some features disabled after 1GB.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ADAT with Digi 002 Consoles - Don&#39;t throw them away just yet!</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/01/25/adat-with-digi-002-console-dont-throw-them-away-just-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 21:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1677</guid> 
      <description>So I got given a Digi 002 console version, which looks like this:
A fairly old style digital audio interface and mixer, which was all the rage back in 2002 when it first came out, but now is often found sitting in the skip. Why? Because it is a Pro-Tools inteface, and Avid stopped supporting it about 5 years ago, so it won&amp;rsquo;t actually work under Pro Tools and Windows 10 (believe me, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Eurorack Technique</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/01/24/my-basic-eurorack-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 05:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1661</guid> 
      <description>I thought it might be of some interest to describe how I use my Eurorack, at lot of the time, in making tracks. I have a 3 oscilator - 3 VCA - 3 filter Eurorack which I use primarily so that the oscilators initially work in unison mode with some slight detuning. I typically use a single loop, arpeggio or pattern that I repeat over the song. Then, partway through a track, I will transpose the octaves of the oscilators and vary the sustain of the envelopes, along with the filters and pulse-width modulation amount, to make a morphing yet harmonious sound texture progression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals of 2015 Summary</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2016/01/17/2015-goals-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 20:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1644</guid> 
      <description>At the start of 2015, I wrote down some goals for 2015. Around half-way through the year, I revisited these goals with some thoughts on how well I&amp;rsquo;d done. Now 2015 is over, I want to reflect on what has been achieved and what hasn&amp;rsquo;t.
I also want to comment on the fact that I am discussing personal things here. A few years ago I was decided that I was going to keep this blog professional and pretty much dry of any thoughts or feelings on my personal life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 5 Recommended Upgrades for your PC</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/12/21/top-5-recommended-upgrades-for-your-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 08:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1633</guid> 
      <description>I have made a lot of different upgrades and modifications to my PC, as you can see here. Some of the upgrades have made more of a difference than others though. Here is what I think you should be concentrating on, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to upgrade.
Solid State Hardisk (SSD) - Solid State hard drives use flash memory instead of the moving disk platters of traditional hard disks. It is the same type of storage as your USB stick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too much Scrolling! - Tips for Dealing with Mouse-Wheel Finger Repetitive Strain Injury</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/12/05/too-much-scrolling-tips-for-dealing-with-mouse-wheel-finger-repetitive-strain-injury/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 17:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1613</guid> 
      <description>Recently I had noticed I&amp;rsquo;d been having quite bad problems with my fingers based on the fact that I had been scrolling the mouse wheel too much when scrolling through web pages. Here are a number of options you can take if you are in a similar situation as me:
Change OS&amp;rsquo;s scrolling speed to its maximum This is the easiest change on most modern OSs, and will result in less scroll movements made by your fingers, because each scroll movement will move the screen down by a full screen height, (equivalent to a page down).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biggest Disappointment Purchases for PC - Razer Tiamat &#43; Lightpack</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/11/08/biggest-disappointment-purchases-for-pc-razer-tiamat-lightpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 19:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1590</guid> 
      <description>As you can see, I buy a lot of bits and pieces for my PC. Occasionally though, I buy something that I feel was a disappointment, or not worth the investment. This post is meant to caution against other people making the same mistake.
Razer Tiamat - 7.1 Surround Sound Gaming Headset, with microphone (http://www.razerzone.com) This was a big dissapointment in a couple of ways. The first, and most obvious in hindsight now I&amp;rsquo;m actually working on spatial audio for a living at BBC R&amp;amp;D, is that 7.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Favourite OSX Apps for Development</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/11/07/favourite-osx-apps-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 12:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1580</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just recently bought a Macbook Pro for myself, after having used a MBP at work for 4 years. I find it to be a really powerful development environment for the development I do, in languages such as Java, PHP, Ruby, Python and JS. Here is what I use day-to-day:
OSX El Capitan I haven&amp;rsquo;t found anything not to like about this upgrade. I don&amp;rsquo;t use a lot of external devices, for which Bruce has found problems with El Capitan&amp;rsquo;s new restricted driver management for Arduinos and others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next Big Thing: Voice Control for Home Automation</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/10/15/voice-control-for-home-automation-having-a-virtual-assitant-in-your-living-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 15:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1568</guid> 
      <description>So, I have totally bought in to the home automation craze that is currently &amp;rsquo;the next big thing&amp;rsquo; in the technology world in 2015. Apple has released iOS 9 with their HomeKit home automation framework, Google have the Nest series of smart devices, and there are numerous emerging competitors and hundreds of devices out there right now that will network together in your home.
For the uninitiated, a &amp;lsquo;virtual assistant&amp;rsquo; is a cloud-connected voice processing system which you can &amp;rsquo;talk&amp;rsquo; to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFTTT.com - Program your Life</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/10/15/ifttt-com-program-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 10:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1565</guid> 
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen If This Then That.com then I encourage you to check it out. It has a number of ways of automating your life, and can do things like text message you when you get mentioned on Twitter, up to deactivate your smart alarm when you&amp;rsquo;re nearing your house. This message will (hopefully) be posted on my Facebook page and my Twitter account, all thanks to IFTTT.com.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scope in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/28/scope-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 17:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1551</guid> 
      <description>I am learning JS for work. This is a pretty good summary of the most common scoping rules in JavaScript:
http://stackoverflow.com/questions/500431/what-is-the-scope-of-variables-in-javascript</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introversion, Extroversion and the BBC Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/28/introversion-extroversion-and-being-a-bbc-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 16:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1533</guid> 
      <description>Whether you agree with Myers-Briggs personality profiling or not, like fellow BBC&amp;rsquo;er Ian Forrester I have found them a useful frame of reference from which to discuss my personality, because I see similarities between my perception of me, and the classification.
I took the Myers-Briggs personality profiling, and it has labelled me on several occasions an INTP:
INTPs are marked by a quiet, stoic, modest, and aloof exterior that masks strong creativity and enthusiasm for novel possibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Completed Eurorack</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/02/completed-eurorack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 08:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1493</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished my 6U Eurorack case. It took me 9 months to build, buying a couple of modules a month.
Goals I wanted to make a self-contained dual voice synthesizer that would interface with my 2x Doepfer Dark Energy MK1s and my Microbrute, on a budget. I also wanted to add some random sound generation features.
I chose to make the synthesizer out of Doepfer modules because they are easy to find cheap second-hand, and also because they are well-engineered.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;d like to Learn More About</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/02/things-id-like-to-learn-more-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 06:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1488</guid> 
      <description>Some things I have been meaning to investigate in my own time, but haven&amp;rsquo;t, because life just gets in the way.
Maths - It might surprise a few people that, as a software developer, I never took maths to A-level. I picked up a bit of maths in my CS degree, but I never really got a firm grounding in it. This has prevented me from understanding and coding advanced stuff in game development, understanding audio to a decent level, and generally doing things in which I consider the more interesting fields of computing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals for the Year 2015 - Midway Update</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/09/01/goals-for-the-year-2015-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 15:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1465</guid> 
      <description>Now that I am midway through the year, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d revisit the goals I set myself at the start of the year, to see what has changed.
Career Goals Settle into my new role at the BBC as Test Manager - I suppose this has not been achieved. I will have more updates soon (hopefully) but a change of direction is likely to happen. Pushing for a place to be opened up in Platform Test to employ someone from the Extend Scheme - This has been achieved, and someone will be joining Platform Test from the Extend scheme in October, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Siri, Apple Earphones and Apple Music Together</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/08/15/use-siri-apple-earphones-and-apple-music-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 20:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1456</guid> 
      <description>This requires you to have a subscription to Apple Music and a 3G/4G/wireless data connection, but it is so useful! Using this tip, you can be walking along with your iPhone in your pocket and your Apple earphones in, and then change music just by pressing a button on the earphones remote control and saying &amp;lsquo;Play (your favourite band)&amp;rsquo;.
1. Activate Siri and subscribe to Apple Music. I used to subscribe to Spotify so I switched to Apple Music when I realised the advantages of the integration on my phone, and the wider selection of music.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Progress</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/07/21/modular-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 19:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1441</guid> 
      <description>My Eurorack modular has been progressing. I&amp;rsquo;ve added several low-cost modules, a Doepfer A-138b audio mixer module so I can mix the audio outputs of the oscilators, the noise output, and my Doepfer Dark Energy modules. I found this so useful with the Dark Energys that I have ordered another mixer. This I can use to mix audio before sending it to the filter, for example, or mix audio before sending it to a VCA to be amplified.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switching Audio between two Soundcards</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/06/21/switching-audio-between-two-soundcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 17:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1420</guid> 
      <description>If you have two soundcards - maybe a normal soundcard for your speakers and maybe a headset with its own audio interface - you will want some way of switching all audio between the two. This is an great little open-source tool to do just that. It works on Mac, and Windows 7 up to 10:
https://soundswitch.codeplex.com/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of the &#39;most visited sites&#39; Grid on Chrome</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/06/21/get-rid-of-the-most-visited-sites-grid-on-chrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1414</guid> 
      <description>Not that I particularly look at anything weird, but when I&amp;rsquo;m showing someone my computer I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have my &amp;lsquo;most visited sites&amp;rsquo; pop up when I fire up Chrome. The following Chrome extension will get rid of the default loading page, and just display a blank page:
https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/empty-new-tab-page/dpjamkmjmigaoobjbekmfgabipmfilij</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Source! Device API and Device API-Android on Github</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/06/21/open-source-device-api-and-device-api-android-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 17:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1410</guid> 
      <description>Two Ruby gems that I contributed to from my days in the BBC&amp;rsquo;s TITAN (Test Tools and Infrastructure) team, have been open-sourced. So finally I can say that I have made proper open-source contributions. The gems are for making automating of Android phones via Android Calabash easier, and are used in a lot of the mobile testing we do at the BBC. Here they are:
https://github.com/bbc/device_api https://github.com/bbc/device_api-android Here is my Github profile, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t look very active on the surface, but I have been contributing to repositories which remain private at the moment, so my history is not visible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instruments That I Use</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/06/21/instruments-that-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 17:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1407</guid> 
      <description>I have a lot of different instruments, both hardware and software, for making music, but here is what I use the most at the moment:
Piano I have an actual electric piano but I don&amp;rsquo;t use the onboard sound engine, preferring to use it as a midi controller for a software piano sound. Recently I bought Ableton Live Full Suite, before I was using the &amp;lsquo;Grand Piano&amp;rsquo; sound from the default install.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 16:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?page_id=1402</guid> 
      <description>I create music and DJ in my free time. I have various music projects on the go at any one time.
My &amp;lsquo;Socialist Synthesis&amp;rsquo; project is an experimental/electronica/ambient/soundscape project:
Summer Sun Highway by Socialist Synthesis
Sound Escapes by Socialist Synthesis
I have released an EP under the &amp;lsquo;Machines Move Mountains&amp;rsquo; project with Ellis Breen. It is experimental/electronica/downtempo:
Unfinished Dreams by Machines Move Mountains
I have released some music under the &amp;lsquo;Concrete Spectre&amp;rsquo; project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Progress</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/06/21/eurorack-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 16:18:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1392</guid> 
      <description>Specs
I have finished filling the top half of my Eurorack case, see above. Here is a list of modules:
Dual VCA - A-132-3 Buffered Multiples - Intellij Buff Mult VCO #1 - A-110-1 VCO VCO #2 - A-110-1 VCO Low Pass Filter - A-120 Multiples #1 - A-180-1 Multiples #2 - A-180-1 Quantizer - A-156 Dual Quantizer Envelope Generator - A-140 ADSR Noise Generator/Random - A-118 Quad LFO - A-143-3 Quad LFO Next Moves:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modular Synthesizers</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/01/30/modular-synthesizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1312</guid> 
      <description>I am putting together a small modular synthesiser setup. Modular synthesizers are synthesizers composed of small individual modules, which are wired up to create a circuit for producing sound. They were very popular in the 1970s, with big bands such as Emmerson, Lake and Palmer, Kraftwerk and Jean Michael Jarre all owning big modular setups:
Modular synthesisers have had a resurgence in recent years with modern versions becoming available. One producer of modular synthesiser modules is Doepfer, a German company who&amp;rsquo;s modular synthesizer standard &amp;lsquo;Eurorack&amp;rsquo; has become very popular recently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals for the Year 2015</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2015/01/17/goals-for-the-year-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 23:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1301</guid> 
      <description>NOTE: I have an update on my progress as of 9/1/2015 here
Motivated by my good friend CheerUpLove.com&amp;rsquo;s reflective style of blogging, and Ian Forrester&amp;rsquo;s many interesting posts, I thought it would be interesting to post something a bit more personal and less technical on this blog.
Now that 2015 is upon us, I am going to take some time to publicly outline my goals for the year, so I can hold myself more accountable to them, and so I can look back on them this time next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>microKORG Original &#43; Novation Impulse 61</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/10/31/microkorg-original-novation-impulse-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 20:16:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1280</guid> 
      <description>I picked up a rather ugly (but very cheap!) customised microKORG, and also the excellent Novation Impulse 61 USB/Midi keyboard controller.
The microKORG I like a lot. It was my first synth, and at first I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense of it. I do agree with the Reddit /r/synthesizers view that it is not the best synth to learn on. Their view is that the best synth to learn on is one with a one-to-one mapping between controls and sound engine parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pioneer DDJ-SR Serato Controller Review</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/09/03/pioneer-ddj-sr-serato-controller-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1269</guid> 
      <description>I decided to buy the DDJ-SR controller because it was cheaper than even the cheapest pair of Pioneer CDJs. I’m no stranger to using a laptop and controller, before the DDJ-SR I used my trusty Faderfox DJ2 controller, which is a basic no-frills ‘play buttons, 3 EQs, crossfader and volume faders’ unit.
I was considering getting the Native Instruments Traktor S4 DJ controller, which is one of the most popular full-size controllers for Traktor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Synthesiser Additions: Microbrute, Nord Drum and Access Virus A</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/08/10/new-synthesiser-additions-microbrute-nord-drum-and-access-virus-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 21:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1251</guid> 
      <description>I bought some new synths.
Access Virus A This is the original 1998 Access Virus A. It, it was a staple synth for trance and electronic music in general for the early 00s. I am very happy that I managed to get this secondhand for less than a MicroKORG. It cost over £800 when it came out in 1998. Old digital synths seem to be unpopular at the moment, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard comments along the lines of &amp;lsquo;if it&amp;rsquo;s digital then I might as well use a plugin in my DAW&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A* Algorithm implementation in Python</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/06/12/a-algorithm-implementation-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 00:24:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1240</guid> 
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve had the idea of creating a text-based Roguelike in C++. This lead me on to think about the game AI experiments that I worked during my degree in Computer Science and A.I.. Essential to game AI is the notion of pathfinding, or finding a path from &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;B&amp;rsquo;, past any obstacles that get in the way. One way to do this is to use the A* algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current Music Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/05/05/music-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 16:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1223</guid> 
      <description>I like to dabble in making and playing music. Here is the equipment and setup that I use.
Ableton Live Intro
This is the DAW I use. I have been using Ableton Live for several years now, and I know my way around it. I have tried others but they never really felt as comfortable. Live comes in three flavours, &amp;lsquo;Intro&amp;rsquo; is the most basic paid-for version. I was surprised how cheap the &amp;lsquo;Intro&amp;rsquo; version was, and how little I find myself needing the features of the more expensive versions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Kindlefire HDX for Development under Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/02/10/kindlefire-hdx-under-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 15:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1193</guid> 
      <description>I wanted to get a Kindlefire HDX running under Ubuntu 12.04 with adb.
First I needed to setup the udev rules:
1. Edit /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules as root, and add the following line (create this file if it does not exist):
SUBSYSTEM==&amp;#34;usb&amp;#34;, ATTRS{idVendor}==&amp;#34;1949&amp;#34;, MODE=&amp;#34;0666&amp;#34; 2. Change the permission of this file by executing the following command as root:
chmod a+r /etc/udev/rules.d/51-android.rules 3. Reload the rules by executing the following command as root:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Computer Build</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2014/01/29/my-computer-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1086</guid> 
      <description>Updated: Reorganised, replaced Tiamat headset for KAVE.
I use my computer a lot, for work (software development), gaming and music production. I wanted to build a high-end computer setup, as I&amp;rsquo;ve always lagged behind with upgrades before. So I gradually have been accumulating and swapping bits around to make the setup above.
Internals
Case Motherboard CPU CPU Cooler RAM Wireless Card Optical Drive PSU Visual
Monitor Backlight GPU Audio
Headphones Soundcard Headset Speakers Speaker Stands Mixer Desktop Microphone Peripherals</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Aeron Chair</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/12/24/aeron-chair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 14:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1173</guid> 
      <description>A good ergonomic chair is a wise investment if you&amp;rsquo;re going to spend a lot of time at your computer. One of the better known ergonomic models is the Herman Miller Aeron Task Chair.
What Other People Say About the Aeron Jeff Atwood (from Coding Horror) says:
In fact, after browsing chairs for the last few years of my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to one conclusion: you can&amp;rsquo;t expect to get a decent chair for less than $500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2013 Career Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/11/17/2013-career-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 03:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1156</guid> 
      <description>2015 Update: The &amp;ldquo;Device Hive&amp;rdquo; project has now been changed to be called &amp;lsquo;Hive CI&amp;rsquo; and it is being maintained by a team of developers at the BBC, which I am no longer a part of. It is in the process of being opensourced, see: http://bbc.github.io/hive-ci/
This year has been quite a busy and eventful one for me.
Connected Red Button At the start of the year, I was working on the Connected Red Button team within the BBC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android Debug Bridge failing to detect emulators under OSX</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/11/17/android-debug-bridge-failing-to-detect-emulators-under-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 02:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1150</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a project at the BBC where we are using the Android command-line tools from the Android Developer Tools, to spin up and terminate series of emulators. I noticed a big problem under OSX where &amp;lsquo;adb devices&amp;rsquo; was failing to register emulators occasionally when we started them up, without any error message, even though they were loaded and quite clearly running in a window on OSX. This was a real problem for our project because we needed absolute parity between emulator process being launched and subsequently being detected by adb.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Haiku Machine</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/07/27/thehaiku-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 02:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1103</guid> 
      <description>I found this awesome cut-up poetry generator, which takes the text of famous poets and builds structured poetry out of it. The guy that made it even developed the underlying algorithm as a research project. I have put a version of a free Amazon EC2 instance, wrote a little twitter bot in node.js, and wired the poetry generator with the twitter bot, and now I have this: https://twitter.com/haikumachine - a twitter bot that posts a haiku every five minutes, derived from Dylan Thomas&amp;rsquo;s poetry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>256 Color VIM on Crunchbang Waldorf</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/06/20/256-color-vim-on-crunchbang-waldorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 22:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1068</guid> 
      <description>To get 256 colors working within terminator in Crunchbang Waldorf, I had to do the following:
Add to ~/.bashrc
export TERM=xterm-256color Install a 256 color VIM colorcheme, see desert256 for example.
Add the following to ~/.vimrc:
set t_Co=256 set t_AB=^[[48;5;%dm set t_AF=^[[38;5;%dm &amp;rsquo;t_Co&amp;rsquo; specifies exactly how many colours VIM can use. The other two lines seem to be Debian-specific color code escape sequences.
If you want 256 color VIM for your root user when you sudo edit, then edit /usr/share/vim/vimrc and copy across your settings from your local ~/.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subversion 1.7 on Crunchbang Waldorf</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/06/16/subversion-1-7-on-crunchbang-waldorf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 03:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1063</guid> 
      <description>I use the excellent http://www.smartsvn.com/ client from WANdisco. WANdisco have been releasing new open-source versions of SVN to the public with new improved reliability, and the client uses one of these versions, 1.7, to offer better performance.
Unfortunately if you choose to upgrade your entire repository to 1.7, this breaks compatibility with the default commandline SVN client on Waldorf which I like to use as well as Smart SVN, for quick &amp;lsquo;svn up&amp;rsquo;s and other commandline magic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iTerm for OSX for a Colourful Terminal Experience</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/06/11/iterm-for-osx-for-a-colourful-terminal-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 16:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1055</guid> 
      <description>iTerm is much better than the standard OSX terminal client, not least because it has compatiablity with xterm256-color terminal emulation. xterm256-color emulation will give your terminal access to 256 colours instead of the usual 16. Much better, not just for looking pretty, but for distinguishing between different types of data in an editor like VIM or even in Cucumber output (see picture above). It&amp;rsquo;s also free.
http://iterm.sourceforge.net
Once installed, you will have to go in to the preferences and set your &amp;lsquo;Report Terminal Type&amp;rsquo; to be &amp;lsquo;xterm256-color&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailing a log file and Running an Application at the Same Time</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/06/11/monitoring-a-log-file-and-running-an-application-in-the-same-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 15:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1038</guid> 
      <description>A quick tip this, but a useful one. You can tail a log file in the background while running a script in the foreground. So for example, I frequently execute the following commands:
1.
tail -f /var/log/httpd.log &amp;amp; /etc/init.d/apache restart 2. (The log file will spool onto the terminal as Apache is restarted.)
3. Once you are finished viewing the log file, foreground the log file process and kill it:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring a Slow Internet Connection in OSX</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/03/01/monitoring-a-slow-internet-connection-in-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 01:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1015</guid> 
      <description>I am currently on holiday in Tenerife, and although I really like it here, one thing I do not like is the internet connection we have in our resort. Sometimes networked applications will just hang with no warning and there will be minutes where it&amp;rsquo;s not clear what is going on. Here are some ways you can find a little bit more about what is happening when an application is slow or seems to hang when you have a poor internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDD Talk</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2013/03/01/tdd-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1001</guid> 
      <description>Recently, myself and two colleagues from the BBC, ran a session on Test Driven Development at the Manchester University &amp;lsquo;Ultimate Programming&amp;rsquo; society. The society is a gathering where students discuss cool things they have done with programming, and occasionally have guest speakers from industry. I found the society online and thought it would be great to get the BBC more involved in the local university happenings.
It is the first outreach project that I have undertaken, and it required a lot of preparation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting a single M2V frame into JPEG under OSX</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2012/04/12/converting-a-single-m2v-frame-into-jpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 15:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=976</guid> 
      <description>I needed to view a single frame of a m2v file that had been encoded by our designers for playing out on TV. The file name was .mpg but in actuality it was a single .m2v frame renamed to be a .mpg. Windows Media Player classic used to display the frame fine when I opened the file normally, under Windows XP. However now I have switched to a Mac, I have found that Quicktime and VLC refused to display the single frame.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java 1.6 on RHEL4</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2012/02/11/java-1-6-on-rhel4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 01:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=967</guid> 
      <description>After I wrote a Java application in JDK 1.6, I was stuck for a while when I realised that the target deployment machine was Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4. RHEL4 does not support Java 1.6 in its default configuration.
Luckily I found this article on the CentOS wiki which included instructions on how to install Java 1.6 on CentOS 4. Remembering that RHEL4 and CentOS 4 are almost identical, I tried the method supplied, and it worked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test Driven Systems Development with Nagios</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2012/02/07/test-driven-systems-development-with-nagios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 14:42:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=956</guid> 
      <description>Nagios can be seen as a automated test tool for systems, just as you would have automated tests for software projects. In test driven development (TDD), you write the tests first, and then use those tests to build up a software project that you can have confidence that it works. We can use this method to build up systems, or networks of systems. Plan out which services and processes should be running on your new systems, and then implement Nagios tests for every one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JSoup Method for Page Scraping</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/09/07/jsoup-method-for-page-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 18:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=938</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of writing a web scraper for the forums on Gaia Online. Previously, I used to use Python to develop web scrapers, with the very handy Python library BeautifulSoup. Java has an equivalent called JSoup.
Here I have written a class which is extended by each class in my project that wants to scrape HTML. This &amp;lsquo;Scraper&amp;rsquo; class deals with the fetching of the HTML and converting it into a JSoup tree to be navigated and have the data picked out of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disabling Control-Enter and Control-B shortcut keys in Outlook 2003</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/07/13/disabling-control-enter-and-control-b-shortcut-keys-in-outlook-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 16:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=924</guid> 
      <description>At work, I still have to use Windows XP and Outlook 2003. I don&amp;rsquo;t particually mind this, except when I draft an email to someone and accidently I press Control-B instead of Control-V. Control-B will go ahead and send your partially composed email, resulting in some embarassment as you have to tell everyone to disregard it.
So I wanted to remove the &amp;lsquo;send email&amp;rsquo; shortcut keys in Outlook 2003. There are two ways of doing this, one involves editing your group policy, which is something only my IT administration team can do, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have to involve them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directory names not visable under ls? Change your colours.</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/05/04/directory-names-not-visable-under-ls-change-your-colours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 16:03:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=910</guid> 
      <description>There is a problem I frequently encouter on Redhat/Fedora/CentOS systems with the output of the ls command. Under those distributions, the default setup is to display directories in a very dark colour. If you usually use a white foreground and a black background on your terminal client (such as Putty) then you will struggle to read the names of the directories under Redhat-based distributions.
There are two soloutions that I have used:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Gumtree Property Adverts with Python and BeautifulSoup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/05/01/scraping-gumtree-property-adverts-with-python-and-beautifulsoup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 14:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=886</guid> 
      <description>I am moving to Manchester soon, and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d get an idea of the housing market there by scraping all the Manchester Gumtree property adverts into a MySQL database. Once in the database, I could do things like find the average monthly price for a 2 bedroom flat in an area, and spot bargains through using standard deviation from the mean on the price through using simple SQL queries via phpMyAdmin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Web Services</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/03/02/restful-web-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 14:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=876</guid> 
      <description>REST (Representational State Transfer) is a way of delivering web services. When a web service conforms to REST, it is known as RESTful. The largest RESTful web service is the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) which you use every day to send and receive information from web servers while browsing the internet.
To implement RESTful web services, you should implement four methods: GET, PUT, POST and DELETE. Resources on RESTful web services are typically defined as collections of elements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Weather Forecast&#39; Calendar Service in PHP</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/02/24/a-3-day-weather-forecast-calendar-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 19:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=857</guid> 
      <description>The BBC provide 3 day weather RSS feeds for most locations in the UK. I thought it would be interesting to create a web service to turn the weather feed into calendar feed format, so I could have a constantly updated forecast of the next 3 days of weather mapped on to my iPhone’s calendar. Here it is on my iPhone:
Overview
The service is separated into five files:
ical.php – this contains the class ical which corresponds to a single calendar feed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Find large files by using the OSX commandline</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/02/22/find-large-files-by-using-the-osx-commandline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:16:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=852</guid> 
      <description>To quickly find large files to delete if you have filled your startup disk, enter this command on the OSX terminal:
sudo find / -size +500000 -print This will find and print out file paths to files over 500MB. You can then go through them and delete them individually by typing rm &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;, although there is no undelete so make sure you know you won&amp;rsquo;t miss them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding files in Linux modified between two dates</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/02/16/finding-files-in-linux-modified-between-two-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 12:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=848</guid> 
      <description>You use the &amp;rsquo;touch&amp;rsquo; command to create two blank files, with a last modified date that you specify - one with a date of the start of the range you want to specify, and the second with a date at the end of the range you want to specify. Then you reference to those two files in your find command:
touch /tmp/temp -t 200604141130 touch /tmp/ntemp -t 200604261630 find /data/ -cnewer /tmp/temp -and !</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing simple email alerts in PHP with MagpieRSS</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/02/12/writing-simple-email-alerts-in-php-with-magpierss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 20:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=842</guid> 
      <description>I wrote an email alerter that sends me an email whenever the upcoming temperature may dip below freezing. It uses the Magpie RSS reader to pull down a 3 day weather forecast that is provided for my area in RSS form by the BBC weather site. It then parses this forecast and determines if either today&amp;rsquo;s or tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s weather may dip below freezing. If it might, it sends an email to my email address to warn me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverting back to a previous version in CVS - the magic &#34;undo&#34; feature</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2011/01/28/reverting-back-to-a-previous-version-in-cvs-the-magic-undo-feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 16:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=836</guid> 
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve committed some code into to CVS, and made a mistake on that commit, you will want to know how to revert to a previously saved version. Here is the command line command for CLI versions of CVS:
$ cvs update -D &amp;#39;1 week ago&amp;#39; Run this command in the main directory of your checked out working copy. This will revert your working copy to the version of the code that was checked in &amp;lsquo;1 week ago&amp;rsquo; from the present date.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netbeans for simple Java GUI Applications</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/12/07/netbeans-for-simple-java-gui-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 17:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=834</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing some simple Java GUI applications using the Netbeans IDE. It allows you to quickly make event-driven GUI applications, and generates a lot of skeleton code that you&amp;rsquo;ll need, but don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily want to type out. It reminds me of the IDE designer of Visual Basic 6, which allowed you to mock up simple GUIs with code in almost no time at all, although the VB language itself often proved difficult.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Converting week numbers to dates</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/11/24/converting-week-numbers-to-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 13:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=823</guid> 
      <description>Here is some python code I adapted from this stackoverflow post to get the first day of a week specificed by a week number. This method includes leap year and summer time differences.
import time def weeknum(num,year): instr = str(year)+&amp;#34; &amp;#34;+str(num-1)+&amp;#34; 1&amp;#34; print time.asctime(time.strptime(instr,&amp;#39;%Y %W %w&amp;#39;)) Here is me exectuting the code in Python&amp;rsquo;s IDLE shell:
See that the first week of 2009 actually started in 2008, but by the end of that week we are in 2009.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac BBC Radio Player</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/11/16/mac-bbc-radio-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 18:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=820</guid> 
      <description>Quite cool little app that allows you to listen to different BBC Radio programmes from within a standalone application, instead of iPlayer:
http://whomwah.github.com/radioaunty/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MediaMonkey allows you to transfer music from any computer onto your guest iPhone</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/11/14/mediamonkey-allows-you-to-transfer-music-from-any-computer-onto-your-guest-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 16:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=813</guid> 
      <description>MediaMonkey is a popular free media player for Windows. It has a great feature that allows you to transfer to and from an iPhone that is not registered with your computer. Normally only one iTunes install can be associated with your iPhone, but MediaMonkey allows you another way to transfer music and audio files with a &amp;lsquo;guest&amp;rsquo; iPhone. Check it out, it works:
MediaMonkey</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applications I Reccomend</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/07/19/applications-i-reccomend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 00:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=802</guid> 
      <description>Software I use on my macbook &amp;amp; PC:
DVDRipper Pro for Mac - DVD ripping, can also rip to ISO Handbrake for Mac - Transcoding from DVD rip to iPhone-playable file iMovie for Mac - Video editing BabasChess for Windows - Best chess client for internet play Hypercam 2 - Best screencapture utility Skype for both - For reliable messaging as well as voice and video chat Virtual Clone Drive for Windows - For mounting ISO images iTunes for Mac - Best music player, and keeps media synced with iPhone VLC Player for both - For watching movies DVD Player for Mac - For watching DVDs</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording Game Videos on Windows 7</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/07/18/798/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2010 23:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=798</guid> 
      <description>This is just a quick note to remind myself how I did this.
Hypercam2 is a good, free, video recorder that can cope with recording game videos. It&amp;rsquo;s freely available from http://www.hyperionics.com/hc/downloads.asp - just make sure when you install it you don&amp;rsquo;t tick on the spyware toolbar installation options.
My motherboard has a 5.1 digital soundcard built in. However the only way I can record off the soundcard is to plug in a standard audio cable from the speaker out (green) to the microphone in (orange).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into a modern Indie Music label</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/07/16/insights-into-a-modern-indie-music-label/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 00:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=788</guid> 
      <description>I read this remarkable post on a public mailing list I subscribe to. I thought it was such a great insight into running a music label, that I just had to post it here. It discusses issues facing modern music, such as DRM, DMCA, and other ways of making (or losing) money. Fascinating.
Here it is:
I work for a (fairly small) indie label - from witnessing this model in action I feel I have to stick up for the label given that I see the model working (or sometimes not so well) on a daily basis!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Ubuntu 10.4&#39;s Bootloader, after a Windows 7 Install</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/07/13/restoring-ubuntu-10-4s-bootloader-after-a-windows-7-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2010 13:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=781</guid> 
      <description>I installed Windows 7 after I had installed Ubuntu 10.4. Windows 7 overwrote the Linux bootloader &amp;ldquo;grub&amp;rdquo; on my master boot record. Therefore I had to restore it.
I used the Ubuntu 10.4 LiveCD to start up a live version of Ubuntu. While under the LiveCD, I then restored the Grub bootloader by chrooting into my old install, using the linux command line. This is a fairly complex thing to do, and so I recommend you use this approach only if you&amp;rsquo;re are confident with the linux command line:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Gaming on my Macbook</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/07/01/running-windows-7-on-my-macbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 22:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=769</guid> 
      <description>I have a 2006/2007 Core 2 Duo 2.6ghz white macbook, that I use regularly for internet, music, watching films, itunes and integration with my iPhone.
I wanted to turn my desktop PC into a &amp;lsquo;work only&amp;rsquo; Ubuntu Linux machine, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted when I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be doing something else.
But I still have a lot of PC games that I wanted to play on the Macbook, so I decided to try and setup a windows environment to play games on using Bootcamp 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ripping Movies onto the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/05/17/ripping-movies-onto-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=762</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently watching Persepolis, the 2008 animated film about a tomboy anarchist growing up in Iran. I&amp;rsquo;m watching this on my new iPhone 3GS, and the picture and audio quality is very good.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I used to convert my newly bought Persepolis DVD, for watching on the iPhone.
1x Macbook (but you can use any intel mac) 1x iTunes 1x RipIt - Commercial Mac DVD Ripper (rips up to 10 DVDs on the free trial, $20 after) 1x Handbrake 32 - Freely available transcoder 1x VLC 32 - Freely available media player 1x DVD</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decent Graphics for Flash Games</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/05/17/art-for-flash-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 02:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=749</guid> 
      <description>Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about making a Flash game or application. Although I haven&amp;rsquo;t made one yet, my current understanding is that most projects of this type require a lot of artwork.
I found this article, and was impressed at the quality and the resources mentioned: http://freelanceflashgames.com/news/2009/03/25/the-big-guide-to-hiring-an-artist/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress HTML edit mode inserts BR tags sometimes when you add a carriage return..</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/04/28/wordpress-html-edit-mode-inserts-br-tags-sometimes-when-you-add-a-carriage-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 20:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=741</guid> 
      <description>This is something that was quite annoying today, as I was struggling to use Wordpress 2.9.2 to align some pictures in the HTML mode of editing a page, on a client&amp;rsquo;s website.
It turns out that Wordpress was adding BR tags sometimes when I hit return.. and sometimes not. The annoying thing was, although the BRs were outputted in the resultant Wordpress site, the BRs were not visible in the Wordpress HTML edit mode itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Forkbombs and How to Prevent Them</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/04/02/forkbombs-and-how-to-prevent-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 03:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=730</guid> 
      <description>A forkbomb is a program or script that continually creates new copies of itself, that create new copies of themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s usually a function that calls itself, and each time that function is called, it creates a new process to run the same function.
You end up with thousands of processes, all creating processes themselves, with an exponential growth. Soon it takes up all the resources of your server, and prevents anything else running on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to remove nano, vim and other editors&#39; backup files out of a directory tree</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/22/how-to-remove-nano-vim-and-other-editors-backup-files-out-of-a-directory-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 20:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=710</guid> 
      <description>Linux command-line editors such as nano and vim often, by default, create backup files with the prefix of &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;. I.e, if I created a file called /home/david/myfile, then nano would create a backup in /home/david/myfile. Sometimes it doesn&amp;rsquo;t delete them either, so you&amp;rsquo;re left with a bunch of backup files all over the place, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re editing a lot on a directory tree full of source code.
Those stray backup files make directory listings confusing, and also add unnecessary weight to the commits on source control systems such as svn, cvs, git.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tip for watching the completion of a large file copy</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/20/tip-for-watching-the-completion-of-a-large-file-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 22:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=695</guid> 
      <description>Forget the wonderful windows progress bar, and imagine I&amp;rsquo;m in the world of command-line Linux, and I want to copy a 484MB file, called VMware-server-2.0.2-203138.i386.tar.gz, from my home directory to a remote server. But I want to figure out how long it&amp;rsquo;s going to take.
1. First I can run a &amp;ldquo;du -m&amp;rdquo; command to get the total MB size of the original file:
du -m /home/david/VMware-server-2.0.2-203138.i386.tar.gz I.e: david@believe:~$ du -m VMware-server-2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Root Directory, Explained</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/20/the-linux-file-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 15:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=572</guid> 
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s helpful to know the basic filesystem on a Linux machine, to better understand where everything is supposed to go, and where you should start looking if you want to find a certain file.
Everything in Linux is stored in the &amp;ldquo;root directory&amp;rdquo;. On a windows machine, that would be equivalent to C:. C: is the main folder where everything is stored. On Linux we call this the &amp;ldquo;root directory&amp;rdquo;, or simply &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful OSX commands for Linux users</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/19/useful-osx-command-line-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 23:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=555</guid> 
      <description>I wrote this list to remind me, as a newcomer to OSX, how the command line differed from the Linux commandline. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d expand on it, and share it:
To mount any iso:
hdiutil mount sample.iso To download a file as you would using wget:
curl http://ftp.heanet.ie/pub/linuxmint.com/stable/8/LinuxMint-8.iso -o linuxmint.iso -C - the -o specifies the output file (required) the -C - specifies automatically resuming if possible.
To burn a bootable iso to CD, DVD or USB key: use the &amp;ldquo;diskutil&amp;rdquo; program as described in: http://forums.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Bash History Files are Great.</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/18/long-bash-history-files-are-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 19:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=543</guid> 
      <description>When I&amp;rsquo;m installing software, or doing some complicated stuff on the linux command line, which nowadays is pretty much all the time, I will sometimes want to remember exactly what I typed.
Now the normal /home/david/.bash_history file is usually fine for that. Run this command, for example, and you will see the commands you typed in before you logged out of the server last time you used it:
cat ~/.bash_history You can also find out what you typed in this session, ie: since you logged in, by typing this:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My minimal VIM config</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/18/my-minimal-vim-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 19:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=535</guid> 
      <description>This is the absolute minimum I do when I have to log onto a new server or shell account that I haven&amp;rsquo;t used before, that I will need to edit text files with.
First I figure out whether VIM is really installed. A lot of installs, especially those based on ubuntu, ship with VI aliased to VIM, but the VIM install is usually not really VIM at all, and behaves exactly like VI but with some minor bugs fixed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the Linux command &#39;Watch&#39; to test Cron jobs and more</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/13/using-the-linux-command-watch-to-test-cron-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=506</guid> 
      <description>OK, so you have added a cron job that you want to perform a routine task every day at 6am. How do you test it?
You probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend all night waiting for it to execute, and there&amp;rsquo;s every chance that when it does execute, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to find out whether it is executing properly - the task might take 30 minutes to run, for example. So every time you debug it and want to test it again, you have to wait until 6am the following day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing the default &#34;From:&#34; email address for emails sent via PHP on Linux</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/10/changing-the-default-from-email-address-for-php/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2010 06:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=475</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had to solve this problem a couple of times at least, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a common task, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d document it here.
When you send emails to users of your site through using the PHP mail() function, they will sometimes turn up in the mailbox of customers of your site with the following from address:
From: Root &amp;lt;root@apache.ecommercecompany.com&amp;gt; This makes absolutely no sense to your customers, and often they will think it is spam and delete it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shell scripts for converting between Unix and Windows text file formats</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/03/09/shell-scripts-for-converting-between-unix-and-windows-text-file-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 00:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=461</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using these shell scripts I wrote to convert between unix and windows text file formats. They seem to work well without any problems. If you put them in the /usr/sbin/ directory, they will be accessible on the path of the linux admin account root.
/usr/sbin/unix2win `#!/bin/bash
Converts a unix text file to a windows text file. usage: unix2win requirements: sed version 4.2 or later, check with sed &amp;ndash;version sed -i -e &amp;rsquo;s/$/r/&amp;rsquo; $1 `</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site Redesign</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/01/14/site-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 07:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=433</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just updated the design of this blog, re-enabled comments and added a contact tab. I&amp;rsquo;ve installed a strong anti-spam comment filter, but you should now be able to comment on entries. I&amp;rsquo;ve also changed the layout of things slightly, and made it easier to read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHP Sample - HTML Page Fetcher and Parser</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/01/14/php-sample-html-page-fetcher-and-parser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 05:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=383</guid> 
      <description>Back in 2008, I wrote a PHP class that fetched an arbitary URL, parsed it, and coverted it into an PHP object with different attributes for the different elements of the page. I recently updated it and sent it along to a company that wanted a programming example to show I could code in PHP.
I thought someone may well find a use for it - I&amp;rsquo;ve used the class in several different web scraping applications, and I found it handy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passed the W3Schools PHP Certification</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/01/14/passed-the-w3schools-php-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 01:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=377</guid> 
      <description>As a break from my contract work, I took the W3Schools PHP Certification. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any revision, which probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t wise. It was a bit more difficult than I thought, but I passed still.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Config files for the Windows version of VIM</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2010/01/10/config-files-for-the-windows-version-of-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 23:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=331</guid> 
      <description>Today I encountered problems configuring the windows version of the popular text editor VIM, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write up a quick post talk about configuration files under the Windows version, if anyone becomes stuck like I did. I use Linux, OSX and Windows on a day-to-day basis, and VIM as a text editor for a lot of quick edits on all three platforms. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick comparison:
Linux Linux is easy because that&amp;rsquo;s what most people who use VIM run, and so it is very well tested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed Climbing</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/10/17/speed-climbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 23:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=304</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a break from the purely technical posts to get more people to see this video. Here the late Dan Osman speed-climbs a cliff without any safety equipment.
http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/v/Fpm0m6bVfrM&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;rel=0
Risky? Just a bit. A few years later he lost his life during a similar attempt. But no-one can doubt the guts required, and the level of skill he achieved, in this type of climbing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regex in VIM.. simple</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/10/07/regex-in-vim-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 06:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=137</guid> 
      <description>There are more than a gazillion ways to use regexs. I am sure they are each very useful for their own subset of problems. The sheer variety can be highly confusing and scary for a lot of people though, and you only need to use a few approaches to accomplish most text-editing tasks.
Here is a simple method for using regex in the powerful text editor VIM that will work well for common use.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heart rate monitor now available for the XO Laptop</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/04/07/heart-rate-monitor-now-available-for-the-xo-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 17:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=108</guid> 
      <description>Volunteers on the OLPC project have developed a low-cost heart rate monitor that can be plugged into the XO laptop, making steps towards an affordable monitoring system for hospitals in developing countries.
For more information on the development, see the: OLPC Goldenstate project. People in the US can currently buy the sensor here; unfortunately there is no international shipping yet in place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirutalHosts on CentOS</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/03/30/virutalhosts-on-centos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 22:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=98</guid> 
      <description>A common task when setting up an Apache webserver under Linux, is writing a httpd.conf file. The httpd.conf file is the main configuration file for Apache. One of the main reasons to edit the httpd.conf file is to setup virtual hosts In Apache. A Virtual host configuration allows several different domains to be run off a single instance of Apache, on a single IP. Each host is a &amp;lsquo;Virtual host&amp;rsquo;, and typically has a different web root, log file, and any number of subdomains aliased to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MicroKORG &#43; Python = MIDI fun!</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/03/30/microkorg-python-midi-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2009 00:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=81</guid> 
      <description>So, about a month ago I got a second-hand microKORG from Ebay. Fiddling around with the preset patches, and creating new patches is great fun, even though I only know a few chords. Recently I plugged it in to my PC via my M-Audio Uno USB-&amp;gt;MIDI interface, and soon was using Ableton Live to program drums in time with the microKORG&amp;rsquo;s arp.
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d experiment the music libraries available in python, and see if I could send notes to the synth via MIDI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eclipse 3.4.2 &#43; Pydev &#43; Eclim = win</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/03/27/eclipse-342-pydev-eclim-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 23:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=74</guid> 
      <description>So, after saying all that stuff about how vimplugin and EasyEclipse was great, I actually started to use the setup heavily, and it started to annoy me.
For one, EE is not a recent build of eclipse, nor does it come with a full set of recent plugins. This makes it annoyingly difficult to use when you want to use more than the set of plugins it packages for you. As far as vimplugin goes, it does not provide the vim integration I thought it might from embedded vim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EasyEclipse &#43; Vimplugin for Python Development</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/03/26/easyeclipse-vimplugin-for-python-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2009 18:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=63</guid> 
      <description>Up until now, I&amp;rsquo;ve always used the terminal for programming development on my projects. Because I&amp;rsquo;m so familiar with the advanced text editor vim, I can get a lot done on the command line, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t detract away from what is actually going on behind the scenes, as a lot of IDEs seem to do.
However, in reading the book Foundations of Agile Python Development (which I recommend highly), and through working in software houses using IDE s only, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realise that I need to gain at least some familiarity with an IDE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Sync for Mobile</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2009/03/11/google-sync-for-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 08:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=56</guid> 
      <description>If you use Google calendar, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got an iPhone, or Windows Mobile phone like me, then you&amp;rsquo;ll be pleased to hear about the new Google Sync for Mobile tool just brought out into beta by Google. There were various ways to sync Google Calender events to Windows Mobile devices before, but nothing officially supported. Google uses an ActiveSync server to push the events to your phone, making things a lot easier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Laptop Per Child - My XO Laptop</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/12/09/one-laptop-per-child-my-xo-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 01:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=29</guid> 
      <description>I did something out of the ordinary this Christmas. I bought an &amp;ldquo;XO&amp;rdquo; laptop for a child in a third world country. I also bought an XO laptop for myself, so I can develop software designed to be distributed to the 1 million+ XO laptops out there in the third world.
The laptop runs a Linux operating system, with an special interface programmed almost exclusively in Python. Most apps, called &amp;lsquo;activities&amp;rsquo;, run as python programs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blog Factory</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/12/03/the-blog-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 22:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=27</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started my own blog consulting business, helping people setup their own blogs, either for their company or for personal use. It&amp;rsquo;s called The Blog Factory, see the site for more information on what we do. In a nutshell, we can:
Setup and customise WordPress blogs. Design custom WordPress themes. Develop tailored WordPress plugins. Host the blogs on our servers. Use our SEO expertise to improve traffic to the blog. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FREE Cloud Computing testbed for Python Apps</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/11/22/free-cloud-computing-testbed-for-python-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2008 05:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=25</guid> 
      <description>This is so cool.. Google are beta-testing a totally free hosting and cloud-computing resource called Google App Engine. The caveat is that your hosted app must be written in Python. Python is amazing anyway, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it, now is the perfect time to learn. Check this out for more information about Google App Engine:
http://code.google.com/appengine/docs/whatisgoogleappengine.html
They&amp;rsquo;re giving away a very generous 500MB disk space and enough processing power to serve 5 million pages a month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bacula Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/10/29/linux-backups-using-bacula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 20:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=24</guid> 
      <description>Bacula is a great open-source distributed backup program for Linux/UNIX systems. It is separated into three main components:
One &amp;lsquo;Director&amp;rsquo; - which sends messages to the other components and co-ordinates the backup One or more &amp;lsquo;File Demons&amp;rsquo; - which &amp;lsquo;pull&amp;rsquo; the data from the host they are installed from. One or more &amp;lsquo;Storage Demons&amp;rsquo; - which &amp;lsquo;push&amp;rsquo; the data taken from the file demons into a type of archival storage, IE: backup tapes, a backup hard disc, etc I found it extremely versatile yet very complicated to configure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux under Hyper-V</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/10/09/linux-under-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 23:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=23</guid> 
      <description>This is an overview of current Linux support under Hyper-V, the free Windows Server 2008 virtualisation product.
As you probably know, virtual servers allow the emulation of hardware in software. So you have a single physical &amp;lsquo;virtual server&amp;rsquo;. This virtual server emulates the physical hardware for several &amp;lsquo;virtual machines&amp;rsquo; which sit on top of the virtual server. As far as the operating system on the virtual machine is concerned, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t notice anything different at all - it thinks it is running on a full set of dedicated hardware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Engineering for Everyone</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/09/22/stanford-engineering-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 23:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=22</guid> 
      <description>The Stanford engineering department, often regarded as the best in the world for computer science education, has made its core CS curriculum free for anyone with an internet connection. There are some catches, ie: you don&amp;rsquo;t get your assignments marked, you have no contact with the lecturer, but all the same, it is really a great resource. The material is very high-quality, professionally filmed lectures and a full compliment of handouts and course notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automated Emails on Commiting to a Subversion Repository Using Python</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/09/22/automated-emails-on-commiting-to-a-subversion-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 23:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=21</guid> 
      <description>At work I&amp;rsquo;ve written a couple of scripts that send out emails to the appropriate project team when someone checks in a commit to the project subversion repository. Here are the details.
Firstly, you will need a subversion hook setup on post-commit. The post-commit hook needs to be located in SVNROOT/YOURPROJECT/hooks where YOURPROJECT is your svn project name, and SVNROOT is the root directory where you are storing the data files for your subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Wikipedia Information for music artists, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/09/22/scraping-wikipedia-information-for-music-artists-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 23:04:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=20</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve abandoned the previous Wikipedia scraping approach for Brightonsound.com, as it was unreliable and didn&amp;rsquo;t pinpoint the right Wikipedia entry - ie: a band called &amp;lsquo;Horses&amp;rsquo; would pull up a Wikipedia bio on the animal - which doesn&amp;rsquo;t look very professional. So instead, I have used the Musicbrainz API to retrieve some information on the artist; the homepage URL, the correct Wikipedia entry, and any genres/terms the artist has been tagged with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character encoding fix with PHP, MySQL 5 and ubuntu-server</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/07/06/character-encoding-fix-with-php-mysql-5-and-ubuntu-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 23:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/2008/07/06/character-encoding-fix-with-php-mysql-5-and-ubuntu-server/</guid> 
      <description>For some reason, under ubuntu-server, my default MySQL 5 character encoding was latin1. This caused no end of problems with grabbing data from the web, which was not necessarily in latin1 characterset.
If you are ever in this situation, I suggest you handle everything as UTF-8. That means setting the following lines in my.cnf:
[mysqld] .. default-character-set=utf8 skip-character-set-client-handshake If you already have tables in your database that you have created, and they have defaulted to the latin1 charset, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to tell by looking at the mysqldump SQL:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scraping artists bios off of Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/06/18/scraping-artists-bios-off-of-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 17:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/2008/06/18/scraping-artists-bios-off-of-wikipedia/</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hacking away at BrightonSound.com and I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a way of automatically sourcing biographical information from artists, so that visitors are presented with more information on the event.
The Songbird media player plugin &amp;lsquo;mashTape&amp;rsquo; draws upon a number of web services to grab artist bio, event listings, youtube vidoes and flickr pictures of the currently playing artist. I was reading through the mashTape code, and then found this posting by its developer, which helpfully provided the exact method I needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>adExcellence Exam passed</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/03/21/adexcellence-exam-passed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2008 07:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/2008/03/21/adexcellence-exam-passed/</guid> 
      <description>I passed the adExcellence exam first time.. woo! It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that difficult really.
&amp;ldquo;David Craddock of iCrossing is accredited as an official Microsoft adExcellence Member. A Microsoft adExcellence Member has completed comprehensive online training on managing Microsoft adCenter search engine marketing campaigns and has demonstrated expert knowledge by passing the Microsoft adExcellence accreditation exam.&amp;rdquo;
As of 21/3/08, I&amp;rsquo;m somehow also now #1 on Google.co.uk for the keyword &amp;ldquo;adExcellence exam&amp;rdquo;.. if that&amp;rsquo;s what you googled for, you probably want the adExcellence main site instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo! Pipes</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/03/17/yahoo-pipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 06:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=14</guid> 
      <description>I have just seen Yahoo! Pipes, and am convinced this is going to change the web. For real.
Data source sites will become &amp;lsquo;content providers&amp;rsquo;, data will be aggregated and filtered from multiple content providers, either by the user or by &amp;lsquo;intermediary&amp;rsquo; sites. The user will be able to choose his &amp;lsquo;data view&amp;rsquo; of the content on the internet, just as Google is currently doing.
This is fascinating stuff if you&amp;rsquo;re involved in the web industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrightonSound.com</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/03/15/brightonsoundcom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 21:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=13</guid> 
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Brighton music events Google maps mashup project: www.BrightonSound.com
It&amp;rsquo;s still developing, but it looks quite good, and we&amp;rsquo;re ready to start showing it off to people. So check it out!
UPDATE: This project is now defunct after running for several years, and is no longer hosted. But thanks for the interest!
.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A poor man&#39;s VMWare Workstation: VMWare Server under Ubuntu 7.10 &#43; VMWare Player under Windows XP</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/02/28/a-poor-mans-vmware-workstation-vmware-server-under-ubuntu-710-vmware-player-under-windows-xp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 23:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=12</guid> 
      <description>I finally setup my Dell Lattitude D630 laptop the way I wanted it last night, and thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick writeup about it. Here is the parttition table:
A 40GB Windows XP partition, with VMWare Player installed, which I will be using for Windows applications that don&amp;rsquo;t play well in virtualised mode (eg media applications). I will also be using it as the main platform for running VMs. A basic 5GB root + 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brighton Barcamp2</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2008/02/22/brighton-barcamp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 02:06:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=11</guid> 
      <description>I will be attending Brighton Barcamp 2 on the weekend of the 14th March, and presenting on a new web project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.
See: http://barcamp.pbwiki.com/BarCampBrighton2 and http://www.barcampbrighton.org/ for more info.
Update: Brighton Barcamp 2 is now over.
This was really interesting, and I learned a huge amount in a very short amount of time. Thanks to everyone who talked to me. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be attending future Barcamps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSocial</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/11/24/opensocial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2007 04:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=10</guid> 
      <description>This is going to be absolutely huge:
[youtube https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RytmNqEHYiE&amp;amp;rel=1]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An interesting blog written by a friend of mine</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/11/12/an-interesting-blog-written-by-a-friend-of-mine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2007 20:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=9</guid> 
      <description>My friend Adam has a blog featuring interesting internet finds. Check it out:
One Idea</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A bit of theory..</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/06/02/a-bit-of-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 14:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=7</guid> 
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to learn a lot about search engines lately, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been starting at an internet marketing firm. I found this excellent list of online materials for university courses related to search engines:
http://clair.si.umich.edu:8080/wordpress/?p=11
In particular, these seem especially relevant:
The Structure of Information Networks - http://www.cs.cornell.edu/Courses/cs685/2002fa/ (a good introduction) Search Engine Technology - http://www1.cs.columbia.edu/~radev/SET07.htm (a great course) Information Retreival and Web Search - http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~mooney/ir-course/ (less math than the columbia course, and thus somewhat easier follow) Networked Life - http://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craiglist opens a Brighton, UK section</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/05/17/craiglist-opens-a-brighton-uk-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2007 02:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=6</guid> 
      <description>I just noticed that US bulletinboard giant Craigslist.com has opened a Brighton UK section of their website! There are a few posts already. At the moment, Gumtree&amp;rsquo;s Brighton Section is massively popular here. I&amp;rsquo;ve recurited several flatmates using Gumtree, and am basing my local housing search around it.
It will be interesting to see how Gumtree.com fares now that Craigslist.com has competition in the Brighton local area.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Nabaztag</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/05/08/my-nabaztag/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 04:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=5</guid> 
      <description>Nabaztag (Armenian for &amp;ldquo;rabbit&amp;rdquo;) is a Wi-Fi enabled rabbit, manufactured by Violet. The Nabaztag is a &amp;ldquo;smart object&amp;rdquo;; it can connect to the Internet (for example to download weather forecasts, read its owner&amp;rsquo;s email, etc). It is also fully customizable and programmable. - Wikipedia.org
Here is our Nabaztag - Francois Xavier:
Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around with poor old Francois&amp;rsquo;s programming..
With the help of OpenNab, a proxy server that masquerades as an official Nabaztag server, you can make your Nabaztag do all kinds of tricks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NVIDIA GeForce4 MX 420 under Ubuntu Dapper Drake</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/04/09/nvidia-geforce4-mx-420-under-ubuntu-dapper-drake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2007 18:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=3</guid> 
      <description>My GeForce4 MX 420 didn&amp;rsquo;t work properly with OpenGL under a fresh install of Dapper Drake. Fixing it, however, proved to be really easy:
Install the nvidia package: $ apt-get install nvidia
Edit /etc/X11/xorg.conf and replace the &amp;lsquo;driver&amp;rsquo; where it says &amp;rsquo;nv&amp;rsquo; with &amp;ldquo;nvidia&amp;rdquo;: Section &amp;ldquo;Device&amp;rdquo; Identifier &amp;ldquo;NVIDIA Corporation NV17 [GeForce4 MX 420]&amp;rdquo; #Driver &amp;ldquo;nv&amp;rdquo; Driver &amp;ldquo;nvidia&amp;rdquo; BusID &amp;ldquo;PCI:1:0:0&amp;rdquo; EndSection
Kill X with control-alt-backspace
Login again and test if it works by running glxgears and glxinfo on the console</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/about-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 18:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.net/about-2/</guid> 
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m David Craddock, I live in Manchester, and have worked in IT and software for the past 20 years, currently as a Principal Software Engineer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The topic of this blog</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddock.net/2007/04/02/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2007 18:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.net/?p=1</guid> 
      <description>This blog will be about my perspective on technology. Anything that catches my interest will be fair game, but mainly it will revolve around internet technology and the development of such.
It will allow me to create an online presence, and to improve my writing skills.
I hope you will find the time to check back on this blog and watch it progress.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
